<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Grass Journal</title>
        <link>https://grassjournal.co/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Grass Journal</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:12:05 -0700</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>My Way Of Explaining</title>
            <link>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:12:05 -0700</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</guid>
            <description>The whole problem of existence
is that we are are like a river, but not
minds always flowing
restless, unable to stop.
Sit
by a river
with me.
See how the water
moves.
Touches
one thing, goes on.
Rest
in a deep pool, behind a log.
It’s cold, this water.
It will wake you up.
This river is you, and me.
The water is your mind.
~~
My first idea to write anything—</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The whole problem of existence<br />
is that we are are like a river, but not<br />
minds always flowing<br />
restless, unable to stop.</p>

<p>Sit<br />
by a river<br />
with me.<br />
See how the water<br />
moves.<br />
Touches<br />
one thing, goes on.<br />
Rest<br />
in a deep pool, behind a log.</p>

<p>It’s cold, this water.<br />
It will wake you up.<br />
This river is you, and me.<br />
The water is your mind.</p>

<p>~~</p>

<p>My first idea to write anything—<br />
anything written has already been wrote.<br />
What new ideas lie<br />
just outside the ideas I already have?<br />
The newness of the old, oldness of the new.<br />
Nothing is new or old<br />
designations told past, said in a certain way<br />
have no meaning.<br />
The running around of everything<br />
isn’t running.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #3</title>
            <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</guid>
            <description>&amp;ldquo;Is there something you want badly?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
And she replied almost greedily, gasping for breath: &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;— and burst into a storm of weeping.
&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; she wept in despair.
&amp;ldquo;You needn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of telling me, Sola dear. Maybe I can get it for you when I grow up.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand. You&amp;rsquo;re so little. No one understands. I don&amp;rsquo;t even understand it myself—day and night.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>&ldquo;Is there something you want badly?&rdquo; he asked.</em></p>

<p><em>And she replied almost greedily, gasping for breath: &ldquo;Yes&rdquo;— and burst into a storm of weeping.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;What?&rdquo; he asked.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know,&rdquo; she wept in despair.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;You needn&rsquo;t be afraid of telling me, Sola dear. Maybe I can get it for you when I grow up.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;You wouldn&rsquo;t understand. You&rsquo;re so little. No one understands. I don&rsquo;t even understand it myself—day and night.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Is it because of the way you&rsquo;re made?&rdquo; he asked, full of sympathy and conscious that the discussion was verging now upon the most intimate secrets of the human body, which it is otherwise customary never to mention — possibly it was wrong of him, but the words had slipped his tongue before he realized.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Yes,&rdquo; she sighed after a little reflection, disconsolately.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;It doesn&rsquo;t matter, Sola dear,&rdquo; he whispered then, and patted her cheek, determined to console her. &ldquo;There&rsquo;s no need to find out. I won&rsquo;t tell anyone. I shall ask Gvendur not to tell anyone.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;So you know, then?&rdquo; she asked, taking the cloth away from her eyes and looking him straight in the eyes &ldquo;— you know?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;No, Sola dear, I know nothing. I&rsquo;ve never had a look; it doesn&rsquo;t matter. And anyway nobody can help it. And when I&rsquo;m a big man, maybe I&rsquo;ll build a house in another country and then you can come and live with me and eat potatoes —&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Potatoes? What do I want with potatoes?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;Like it says in the Bible stories,&rdquo; he explained.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;There aren&rsquo;t any potatoes in the Bible stories.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I mean what the woman ate in the Bible stories,&rdquo; he said.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t want anything in the Bible stories,&rdquo; she said, gazing into space with tear-swollen eyes. &ldquo;God is an enemy of the soul.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>Then suddenly he asked: &ldquo;What did you wish for in the winter, Sola, when the teacher gave us all a wish?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>First she looked at him searchingly, and the squint in her eyes seemed more pronounced than ever, because of her weeping; then her lids fell and she began uprooting grass from the sward. &ldquo;You mustn&rsquo;t tell anyone,&rdquo; she said.</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;No, I shall never tell anyone. What was it, then?&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;It was love,&rdquo; she said, and then once more her weeping burst its bonds, and again and again she repeated from the midst of her sobbing: &ldquo;Love, love, love.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;How do you mean?&rdquo; he asked.</em></p>

<p><em>She threw herself in a heap on the ground again, her shoulders shaking with sobs as they had done when he came up to her a few moments ago, and she wailed:</em></p>

<p><em>&ldquo;I wish I could die. Die. Die.&rdquo;</em></p>

<p><em>He did not know what to say in the face of such sorrow. He sat in silence by his sister&rsquo;s side in the spring verdure, which was too young; and the hidden strings in his breast begin to quiver, and to sound.</em></p>

<p><em>This was the first time he had ever looked into the labyrinth of the human soul. He was very far from understanding what he saw. But what was of more value, he felt and suffered with her. In years that were yet to come he relieved this memory in song, in the most beautiful song the world has known. For understanding the soul&rsquo;s defencelessness, of the conflict between the two poles, is not the source of the greatest song. The source of the greatest song is sympathy. Sympathy with Asta Sollilja on earth.</em></p>

<p><strong>— Independent People</strong></p>

<p><img src="/img/19.3-tent.jpg" alt="wallowa-oregon" /></p>

<p>As I drove south through the storm, the lights of Taos flickered in and out on the horizon. The snow coated the road, and driving was slow. The jeep had turned off, and I was alone. It was the hour of reflection. There was nothing to do but drive slowly, watching the road, careful with traction, looking for the edges so as not to get stuck in my little four door sedan. It lent a measure of tension to the reflections that passed through my mind.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easy to go along and think: I understand this or that. Because the available material to work with, the few facts at hand, may create what looks like a full picture. The fact is, though, without knowing the full story of something, it&rsquo;s impossible to know the complete truth. And stories can change, depending on moods, who is telling them, what is remembered and forgotten. So what is this reality we live in after all?</p>

<p>Who am I, and what am I doing? I thought I had put these kinds of questions to rest a long time ago. But now, in my thirtieth year, I found that once again they came up, again and again. This nagging idea, that the story of my life wasn&rsquo;t the point of it all, had never gone anywhere, I had never answered it. If anything, it had gone deeper, and now, at age thirty, when &ldquo;something was supposed to have happened,&rdquo; some career, some knowledge of the future, some success—absolutely nothing had. Even the goal I had set out to achieve four years before, which seemed reasonable to me at the time: to find a place to call home, hadn&rsquo;t been achieved. The only thing I felt I had learned was that there was never a final answer to anything.</p>

<p>In the past my answer has been &ldquo;my art&rdquo; to the question of &ldquo;who are you.&rdquo; But as time has gone on, and my ideas of what it means to be successful have changed, and more questions have come up about the function and worth of art, and where it is useful, and who wants it, I began to doubt that. Maybe it was just a fanciful interpretation of life arisen from an easy time in my twenties. Of course people should produce beauty. Looking at the world closely, how could one not? What I had really come down to was this: did my life&rsquo;s work matter to anyone else? For so long I had studied and absorbed the world, books, films, recipes, experiences. And in the back of my mind I had this idea of a reservoir of experience, building up to a shining fullness, and from that deep, bountiful place I could draw things, write things, photograph things, say things, cook things that would somehow contribute to the world around me. But in my thirtieth year, I found the world more broken than ever. The ways my friends communicated dominated by platforms engineered to be addictive. People&rsquo;s attention spans shorter, and anxieties higher. City living incredibly stressful and expensive. Rural living lonely and isolating. The art, publishing, and photography worlds run by money, with frail offshoots of goodness. People&rsquo;s egos getting in the way of real work. But I refused, all along, to give up the kernel question, the question from which it all sprang from for me: &ldquo;What really matters?&rdquo;</p>

<p>But who am I to answer such a thing, even just for myself? And trying to answer it for others? Laughable.</p>

<p>At a certain point in this quest, photography and Instagram failed me. And then words, in the way I wrote them, failed me. But, just over a year ago, I began writing about all of this anyway. I wanted to make it congeal, to have some solution from it, to understand it. So I wrote, in the night after working during the day, on a farm on an island in Maine. The writing saved my life, and gave me hope, as the time on that island was amongst the most difficult so far in my life.</p>

<p>The writing came out as poems, instead of prose. It broke down into lines of simplistic sentences, more like short stories than anything. Over the last year I wrote almost 200 pages of this kind of writing, which I titled &ldquo;A Body Of Water.&rdquo; Pretty much no one, besides one or two people, have seen or heard from that work. In the midst of writing it, I realized that to some degree my questions had been answered, in that there was no answer to them. I would just have to go along and find out. Experience would offer me what I was looking for, and then again it may never.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s strange how the idea of quitting an attempt to understand something can, to me, seem almost as absurd as ever answering the question itself. And I guess that&rsquo;s where I leave it.</p>

<hr />

<p>As I slid into town the snow thickened, falling like flour under the orange streetlights on Paseo del Pueblo Sur. Cars had gone off the road, I counted six. The hill past the plaza was sloppy, and I turned into the curb to prevent sliding into an intersection. Everyone else was driving around gingerly, the whole world coated in pure, beautiful new snow.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #2</title>
            <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</guid>
            <description>After leaving the retreat, I headed west and then south, across and then down the wide valley. There is only one highway bisecting the valley, mountains bordering the east, and sagelands expanding to the west. At the base of the mountains lie a huge series of pale dunes, heaped up sand and dust accumulated there over millennia, blown there by the wind.
Snow began to fall and then it was dark.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After leaving the retreat, I headed west and then south, across and then down the wide valley. There is only one highway bisecting the valley, mountains bordering the east, and sagelands expanding to the west. At the base of the mountains lie a huge series of pale dunes, heaped up sand and dust accumulated there over millennia, blown there by the wind.</p>

<p>Snow began to fall and then it was dark. Snow formed drifts the road, and stuck to the cold asphalt. I drove slowly, behind a jeep with their brights on, passing only one or two people as we crossed the state border.</p>

<p>The imaginary world that spread out beyond the headlights was full of my own thoughts, projections of what might be there. A massive, flat topped mesa? Or the Cañon de Rio Grande, where the land suddenly breaks off, space opens up, and a thread thread of green-blue runs at the bottom? Sagebrush, certainly, for miles and miles: the infinite void of sagelands that spread, almost unbroken, from here in New Mexico to southern Canada.</p>

<p>As I drove I thought more about the retreat. I had decided I would not go to another in that tradition. I had gone because I’d never been to something like it. It was hard to know what a retreat was, and how I felt about it, before I went. To me, it felt as though a sacred tradition and culture was being sold, but I wrestled with these thoughts for weeks and even months afterwards. Was it just my own anti-establishment mindset? Or was I seeing through falsity and appropriation?</p>

<p>While at the retreat, I had taken one morning off to go into the mountains. There was a stream flowing down, winding through aspens and cottonwoods. Ice in the stream, a little snow here and there. As I walked a dog appeared out of the trees. Seeing me she stopped, and looked expectantly. I said the magical words: “do you want to go?” And soon she was racing ahead, looking back every now and then to make sure I was still following.</p>

<p>She led me higher and higher, back and forth across the icy stream, across roads, always looking back and waiting for me—all the way to the base of the mountains. She stopped for a drink of water, gingerly stepping on clear ice and breaking through, wetting her paws. It was strange, to meet a new friend like this, that needed no words or even a common species to experience something together. She was self-composed, she knew where she was, and where we were going. I could have walked as far as she wanted, up into the mountains, following the stream up to a lake. But we had been walking for an hour, and I knew I needed to head back. As I turned away from the path, which had began to slant upward and leave the trees behind, I wondered how far into the mountains, on this narrow path, that this simple, honest dog would have led me.</p>

<p>When I arrived back at the car, I noticed that she had followed me all the way back. She stood at the edge of the trees, looking towards me, but not coming any closer. She had a collar, and a home—she didn’t really “need” me. But like anyone, I guess she had found walking with someone more enjoyable than going around alone. And I guess this is what I needed too—companionship, love, and someone to look for me and to look for, as we go along this old trail together.</p>

<p><img src="/img/19.3-dog.jpg" alt="19.3-dog" /></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Story About a Meditation Retreat, #1</title>
            <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</guid>
            <description>The big mountains rose quickly from the flat piñon plain below. Massive, snow-capped mountains, and a sixty mile wide valley broke the scale of distance I was used to. And the weird piñons, with their twisted, old trunks, low tops, many branches: more like oaks than pine trees; held a strange presence. The plain itself savanna-like, with low grass and sagebrush, antelope, and slow-moving mule deer, who I would see in the mornings along the dry watercourses, under black cottonwoods.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The big mountains rose quickly from the flat piñon plain below. Massive, snow-capped mountains, and a sixty mile wide valley broke the scale of distance I was used to. And the weird piñons, with their twisted, old trunks, low tops, many branches: more like oaks than pine trees; held a strange presence. The plain itself savanna-like, with low grass and sagebrush, antelope, and slow-moving mule deer, who I would see in the mornings along the dry watercourses, under black cottonwoods.</p>

<p>I had driven north from Taos, through the wide valley to attend a meditation retreat in the Tibetan Bön tradition, an old tradition mixing Tibetan cultural practices and Buddhism. The retreat cost around $300 for a few days sleeping in a house and a few days sitting in a big circular room, listening to a rinpoche (lit. precious one) talk about Dzogchen, a type of meditation that involves relaxation and a unique lack of effort.</p>

<p>When I arrived, the first thing I noted was the number of new-model cars parked for the retreat. The majority were under five years old. A woman immediately walked up to me and said “are we supposed to park here? I’m gonna move my car. I think we’re supposed to park over there. I don’t think we can park here. I don’t know where.” She gestured vaguely towards a road running into the vast expanse of sagebrush. I shrugged and just kept walking.</p>

<p>At the entrance I was confronted by two people checking lists for names, other people milling about, a variety of scarves, shawls, baggy clothes, hiking boots, and Patagonia jackets piled in corners. The light came in precisely, very clearly, through floor to ceiling windows. It was like the light always is in the high mountains, acute and intense. We were at around 8,000 feet. Outside the mountains rose to over fourteen.</p>

<p>As I settled down on a meditation cushion in the middle of the circular conference room, a man with an unplaceable accent sat next to me. He grew up in Israel, and was Jewish. “Do you practice?” I asked. No, not really, he said. He comes to these things once or twice a year. He’s a massage therapist. He asked me what I did. I said I wandered around and wrote, making money however I could. He said I looked like a professor, but that I should give it a few years.</p>

<p>As we sat for the beginning, he leaned over from time to time to let me know what was going on. We did tsa-lung practice, a type of energetic breath and body work made to be done seated that “opens chakras.” Having never been to a retreat, but practicing meditation for about ten years alone, I found it strange to be in a room of around a hundred people, all saying the Sanksrit syllable “Ah” and imagining white light entering our bodies. Everyone else was ok with it.</p>

<p>As the first morning progressed, I was struck by the humor and ease of the rinpoche. He said things like “just leave it as it is,” and “just relax,” and also “you have reflected enough!” He took questions, and carefully avoided going into people’s personal experience. He was skilled at answering questions.</p>

<p>On the second day, I put up my hand and, while asking a question, made a joke. Several people laughed, as they had at many of the jokes he made. But he had an air of irritation, and as I continued my question, he said “what, is this funny or something?” I got the feeling that he was the one who could make jokes, make people laugh. Others were not allowed that liberty.</p>

<p>On the third and final day, we went outside for a puja. I had seen such things on documentaries, notably The Wheel of Time by Werner Herzog, where a massive hill of incense, juniper, pine wood, prayer flags, and other offerings are piled and set fire to. For our puja we had one of those cast braziers you might see at a suburban home, with a rusty metal grate. Inside a fire of piñon was made, and I was tasked with placing the crumbling, burning incense around the mesh. Rinpoche read a lot of Tibetan and everyone stood around silently, as the smoke billowed feebly from the fire, smelling like nothing really. We each took a handful of barley flour and threw it into the air, which I had also seen. In the video of the Tibetan people at the base of the Himalayas, this scene had the cameraman wading into throngs, people screaming and yelping, bells crashing, and smoke overwhelming the video, turning the screen opaque. Glimpses of weathered brown faces flitted across the screen, heavy woolen robes tied at the waist, prayer wheels, malas, lung-ta billowing, and smoke, smoke, smoke. But around me I saw the pale faced people, in nylon jackets, blankly talking and looking bored, throwing the barley when told to, laughing when queued, being silent when not, below snowy mountains that were not dissimilar to the Himalayas.</p>

<p>As I walked away, a tall white guy with long dreads came up to me. His name was Juniper, and he was from this area. He said: “we’re trying to start a little community here. I have some land. It’s an AirBnB. Next time you come through, let me know. You can stay at our AirBnB.”</p>

<p>I headed to my car, and drove back to the newly built retreat house, to stay one last night. The house looked like it had been airlifted from a subdivision outside Omaha, Nebraska, except it was on an incredibly steep hillside, surrounded by piñons, below the snow-covered mountains. There were new washer-dryer front loading units, a giant island, new fridge, dimmable lighting, soft-closing cabinets, shiny hardwood floors. Everything inside was clean, white, new, unmarked, pure. And very, very expensive.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
