<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Grass Journal</title>
    <link>https://grassjournal.co/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Grass Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:16:44 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Myth Time</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/myth-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 08:16:44 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/myth-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-August/25-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myth Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rocks to soft moss after a day of rain.&lt;br&gt;
Sitting by the fire for hours.&lt;br&gt;
Walking into the meadow flat for more wood&lt;br&gt;
under dry spruce groves&lt;br&gt;
where nothing grows and needles fill the alcoves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then laying for seven hours at night&lt;br&gt;
to hear barred owls fly across the lake, telling tall tales&lt;br&gt;
and land on an island in the lake, to raise their children&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​		&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Once, long ago, all animals were people, and&lt;br&gt;
​		there were no people.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;​		Back in myth time, as the owls grow larger with each word they say&lt;br&gt;
​		living still in myth time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up 2000&amp;rsquo; to Lost Lake, and down to camp.&lt;br&gt;
Rain came again and stoking the fire&lt;br&gt;
to boil white fir for tea&lt;br&gt;
all day long.&lt;br&gt;
Mist like muslin clings to peaks.&lt;br&gt;
Blue steel cup, somewhat rusty, that Jacob uses to drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piles of wood and stacks of branches our currency&lt;br&gt;
to transform to light and heat.&lt;br&gt;
The fire only thing that seemed real that day&lt;br&gt;
the rest of the world locked in mist, far away&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;myth time.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hundreds of bats against the ink blue sky at night.&lt;br&gt;
Downpour and small lake formed&lt;br&gt;
under Teal &amp;amp; Jacob&amp;rsquo;s tent.&lt;br&gt;
Cursing the high use of the area, but falling asleep easily&lt;br&gt;
to the rain, feeling warm&lt;br&gt;
wishing I was&lt;br&gt;
nowhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wake first in morning, like on special days.&lt;br&gt;
Watch orange mist make swirls and spiral into the air for an hour&lt;br&gt;
the light change on the lake, and listen to silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun gets up and there is hope again.&lt;br&gt;
Two pikas squeak in a rockslide as I run up to a ridge coated in wildflowers, alone&lt;br&gt;
but for four deer&lt;br&gt;
making their way&lt;br&gt;
down the trail—&lt;br&gt;
One buck with fuzzy antlers pauses, lets me watch him&lt;br&gt;
and parts the dew so I may pass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the ridge edge looking into another drainage&lt;br&gt;
I spy a hanging meadow of green grass and spruce&lt;br&gt;
—&lt;em&gt;just a little farther, maybe an hour around that cornice,&lt;br&gt;
then down into the cirque on rolly-polly rocks&lt;br&gt;
then up a small ridge—&lt;/em&gt; and I&amp;rsquo;d be there&lt;br&gt;
a place where I could both live, and die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But back down the the soaking trail&lt;br&gt;
to pick up my sweater off a stump&lt;br&gt;
then through a meadow filled with boulders and flowers&lt;br&gt;
to my friends and family&lt;br&gt;
and a long hike together&lt;br&gt;
back to where we began.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flowing Heart Of The Mountain</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-flowing-heart-of-the-mountain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 18:00:27 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-flowing-heart-of-the-mountain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe there will be a place&lt;br&gt;
there may be a place, there could be a place:&lt;br&gt;
A high ridge&lt;br&gt;
Littered with white rocks&lt;br&gt;
Above a flat valley&lt;br&gt;
free of snow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Green things growing in the valley below.&lt;br&gt;
A stream flows through the middle, there may be a place,&lt;br&gt;
there &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; be a place&lt;br&gt;
if you stay on the ridge for long enough&lt;br&gt;
looking down at the valley for about&lt;br&gt;
a thousand years&lt;br&gt;
enough to see the bristlecones grow and some die&lt;br&gt;
and some live, there may be a place&lt;br&gt;
—a place on a high ridge&lt;br&gt;
there may be a place there where you can sit and watch&lt;br&gt;
as the boulders do&lt;br&gt;
for a long time&lt;br&gt;
the water flow out of a spring in the side of a hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There: the cow valley, once aspen ground,&lt;br&gt;
now thigh bones bleached white near the stellar&amp;rsquo;s jay&amp;rsquo;s spruce.&lt;br&gt;
In the center of valley&lt;br&gt;
there are a few rocks covered with orange lichen&lt;br&gt;
—yellow, blue, green, and red—&lt;br&gt;
the sunsets too, you can see&lt;br&gt;
when sitting at the far end of the valley&lt;br&gt;
where a chipmunk lives above the stream&lt;br&gt;
and sits out on his porch to watch the whole valley, forever&lt;br&gt;
but only for a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long enough to know where life comes from, living above the stream itself&lt;br&gt;
as it flows perfectly clear and cold&lt;br&gt;
from below his rockside home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear at the source, the water cuts deeply where the cows go too many times&lt;br&gt;
and muddies before the marsh halfway across.&lt;br&gt;
The marsh is drying, and the snow less every year.&lt;br&gt;
And I lay under engelmann spruce,&lt;br&gt;
my head on a tussock.&lt;br&gt;
A place where the stream is half muddied, and still maybe as it was once&lt;br&gt;
clear and drinkable straight from the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My eyes drift from sky to land to water.&lt;br&gt;
To hear the burble of this glassy fluid, one has to listen.&lt;br&gt;
A small bee lands not an inch from my eye&lt;br&gt;
and cleans his antennae off patiently&lt;br&gt;
then flies off to save the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hear if you lay there long enough&lt;br&gt;
the rocks begin to speak&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;though you are very small&lt;br&gt;
you are very important&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
They whisper to the stream&lt;br&gt;
and the bee&lt;br&gt;
and the chipmunk&lt;br&gt;
to the wind, the trees&lt;br&gt;
the groves of nettles under fir trees,&lt;br&gt;
and they say this&lt;br&gt;
to me—&lt;br&gt;
The flowing heart of the mountain.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Things In The Instagram Era</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/making-things-instagram-era/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 10:20:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/making-things-instagram-era/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got really burned out on photography a few years ago because I felt like posting photos online had become a game of trying to appease an algorithm that was based on making people addicted to staring at teabag sized images on their phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I felt lost in trying to fight to be seen when the content I make is not really popular or trendy. So I gave up, as I felt that the work and time I spent with that medium wasn&amp;rsquo;t valuable anymore—people&amp;rsquo;s focus and attention had shifted. There was and is a surplus of images to the point of saturation. And maybe I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really taking all that interesting of photos anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now, I am finding my way back into taking photos again, but with a different purpose behind the work. As I can&amp;rsquo;t find the energy to try and compete on social media for likes, views, and followers, I want to take the work back to the medium where it started, in print. The problem is, printing is expensive, and the audience, without a following, so small I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine breaking even on a small book series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve explored all avenues and done many of them, such as having lots of followers on Instagram, running a newsletter, blogging, running a kickstarter, getting grants and residencies, etc. The problem is, to get a lot of reach or success with all those things essentially requires two things: either you become your own agent of promotion with a stacked CV or a lot of followers, or you find an agent ie: pay someone to promote you. It&amp;rsquo;s all mixed up with money and ego, which really have nothing to do with what I&amp;rsquo;m trying to create and why—it might even be antithetical to the work itself. I&amp;rsquo;m being idealistic, I realize, when I don&amp;rsquo;t want to play all those games. But if a person doesn&amp;rsquo;t compromise their vision, is it necessary that they have to settle for something different than those that do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at the same time this doesn&amp;rsquo;t really lead me into wanting to spend effort making things that no one will ever see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that this last thought gets down to the root of the matter, which is &amp;ldquo;why make anything?&amp;rdquo; Discussing that, however, leads down a rabbit hole about ego and meaning and contribution. To keep it more simple, this is why I make things: I write and take pictures because I love to. And from past experience I feel people benefit when they encounter my work, or at least enjoy it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in order to continue in this way, it seems like I need to really give up on the idea that I will ever be canonized, famous, or important to anyone other than a small group of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, what a relief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be nice to just keep living the life I have now, now that I think about it. Yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s not so bad after all! Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll even start taking photos of things again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-May/28-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Dream I Had Last Night</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-dream-i-had-last-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 07:54:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-dream-i-had-last-night/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I dreamed I was in a house. I went outside and sat in tall green grass. It seemed like I was in the plains somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sat down in the grass a small white tail buck came up to me. His grey fur and white chest. One of his antlers was broken off. He laid down in the long green grass beside me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a pronghorn antelope with black antlers came up to me. He had tawny fur and black markings and a white chest. He laid down in the grass next to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a big horn ram came up to me. They have grayish brown fur like rocks on a mountain. He laid down in the grass beside me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then an animal I don&amp;rsquo;t remember came up and laid down in the grass beside me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat there surrounded by these four animals. They sat there looking at me. We just sat breathing and looking at each other. There were no words—but things were said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got up and went and sat on a bench. A few people sat there that I had once been friends with, but something happened and now we aren&amp;rsquo;t friends anymore. But we just talked like we were friends again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I woke up to light rain outside. Then I was awake for a while. I heard thunder rumble three times for a long time. Then I fell asleep again after the rain ended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wild Finds A Way</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-wild-finds-a-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 06:49:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-wild-finds-a-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This morning, as I sat at the birch table, I heard a stick break outside the window. I stood up and looked out onto the courtyard. Ambling across the brick patio was one of the largest raccoons I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. She tentatively looked around as she walked around the corner of the house and down the driveway, toward Agua Fria street.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a few minutes she was back, but this time with a young raccoon in her mouth. She headed straight for the overgrown ivy bush at the back of the house, and disappeared into it through an area that seemed far too small and dense to swallow such a huge animal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All day she has been sleeping there, with who knows how many young children raccoons stashed behind the overgrown ivy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This overgrown yard, filled with beautiful desert weeds, lizards, and rare birds. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s the little saucer of water we fill every day that keeps them all coming back. It&amp;rsquo;s a dry patch along a busy street,  yet somehow wildness finds a way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the bridge we crossed a dry river&lt;br&gt;
that went underground after a clear lake.&lt;br&gt;
Across the road it bubbled up again&lt;br&gt;
in a place called Fish Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water of the lake it came out of&lt;br&gt;
was so perfectly clear, and cold&lt;br&gt;
that you could see old stumps and tree&amp;rsquo;s bones&lt;br&gt;
—when it had been a meadow once, long ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People now paddled lazily&lt;br&gt;
with no motors in sight&lt;br&gt;
above the deep, cold, clear lake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat beside a huge tree with my mom&lt;br&gt;
then we drank straight from a spring that rushed out of a hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things like this just happen,
and keep going on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mom says:		&amp;ldquo;I like to know&lt;br&gt;
that this spring we sit beside, and drink&lt;br&gt;
is still running, no matter where I am&lt;br&gt;
or what I think.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The water stays clear,
if we can keep it that way—&lt;br&gt;
in that place that is far away from me now,
yet also right here.&lt;br&gt;
A place I call Clear Clear Lake.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Need?</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/what-we-need/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 12:39:07 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/what-we-need/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do we have what we need? I sometimes wonder what I really need. Food, water, shelter, clothing, right? And yet, and yet as time has gone on it seems I have taken on more epicurean sorts of needs. Tea, sourdough bread, cookies with the tea, certain mugs and tents, other backpacking gear&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how long I could go without certain things, and if I would miss them or not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I miss is a sense of community. I think everyone is feeling that nowadays. Community doesn&amp;rsquo;t really exist online. It has to involve inhabiting space with people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wonder how much we need, and how much we all miss, and if that will change as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a theory that successive generations of people do not sense the loss of environments or animals because we are born into a world where there is a new baseline. So I guess it is also possible to say there are things that we &lt;em&gt;cannot know&lt;/em&gt; that we miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I am listening to &lt;a href=&#34;https://music.youtube.com/watch?v=bQAF2PPz4Ag&amp;amp;feature=share&#34;&gt;Erik Satie&lt;/a&gt;. I took a few photos on a film camera from the 70s that I got off ebay last week&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—The crank winds the film with a ratcheting sound. The exposure is shown on a needle in the small viewfinder. The leaf shutter clicks and the picture scene is imprinted—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe film photography is something I missed. I notice that I am noticing even more—looking for those old angles and patterns of light. And yet the ability and desire to write also has not ceased. Maybe, if I can keep up both of these things up I will get to where I have always been going. Which looks like, to me, a greater awareness of being filled with whatever each moment has to offer. It may sound woozy or sentimental, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found that even the feeling of warm pavement on my feet feels as good as almost anything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do you go?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some end of a road&lt;br&gt;
In a dense thicket of blackberry brambles&lt;br&gt;
bursting sticky fruit scenting the hot summer air&lt;br&gt;
covering the black asphalt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do you go?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Some end of the road&lt;br&gt;
The side trails, &lt;em&gt;you can still see&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;important.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
They lead under cedar boughs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where do you go?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Under the gravel of the river beyond&lt;br&gt;
Are bones of the earth&lt;br&gt;
The beginning of another road&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always the end is a beginning&lt;br&gt;
Of infinite endings and beginnings&lt;br&gt;
Spreading out in all directions&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Where do you go?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
And how do you know&lt;br&gt;
it is worth the going?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waves under waves&lt;br&gt;
soothe the gravel into sand&lt;br&gt;
an estuary, a bog&lt;br&gt;
dipping clear water&lt;br&gt;
from a rainwater pond&lt;br&gt;
to drink for breakfast&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunrise, sunset&lt;br&gt;
this is the beginning&lt;br&gt;
and end&lt;br&gt;
of this song.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Hike</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/why-i-hike/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 12:36:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/why-i-hike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few weeks, precluded from leaving the house much, I have been watching out the back window at the birds that have come to drink from a basin of I water I fill each day. In particular one bird, a canyon towhee, is often there. He is much bigger than the other birds and therefore distinct. He is &amp;ldquo;native&amp;rdquo;, whereas many of the others are european imports. But anyway, as time has gone on and I&amp;rsquo;ve had nothing to do, I have really grown fond of this big sparrow shaped bird. Though he&amp;rsquo;s not that impressive in color, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t have much of a song, he has a strong personality, and likes to root around under the apple tree, throwing sticks and leaves everywhere, in his search for food. I realized yesterday, as I saw him getting ready to sleep in the old dead tree across the alley (where he sleeps every night), how sad I would be if I one day found him dead. There are some really rough cats that prowl the alley and I always haze them by yelling (sorry cat lovers, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/national/health-science/outdoor-cats-kill-between-14-billion-and-37-billion-birds-a-year-study-says/2013/01/31/2504f744-6bbe-11e2-ada0-5ca5fa7ebe79_story.html&#34;&gt;cats kill billions of birds every year&lt;/a&gt;) and I thought also about how terrible it would be if this rare bird (canyon towhees are really rare in towns) got killed by someone&amp;rsquo;s cat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this to say—since we&amp;rsquo;re all cooped up inside, and all staring at screens too much, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to remember what&amp;rsquo;s real and what&amp;rsquo;s not. All the images we see on the screen neither live, nor die. They are just there every day in this endless feed, producing good and bad emotions, thoughts, etc. Yet if one of those images that we spend so much time looking at blinked out, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even notice. There are so many that it&amp;rsquo;s not even like they have any vitality to them at all. They are disposable before they even enter your consciousness—they are less memorable than breathing. And yet so much is wrapped up in those images and screens nowadays—which is a landscape not of vitality but of endless unimportance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My thought is this: focusing on what we can see, even out our backdoor window, is sometimes more meaningful than the things our brains get hooked on and tell us to keep consuming. It&amp;rsquo;s a different kind of attention that&amp;rsquo;s needed to draw one to this &amp;ldquo;less interesting&amp;rdquo; experience. But the important part is that it actually makes us care about something, love something, connect with something—and maybe more importantly, want to protect it. And I guess that&amp;rsquo;s part of why I go hiking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anxiety &amp; The Present Moment</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/anxiety-the-present-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 03:18:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/anxiety-the-present-moment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I was taught one of two reactions when things go wrong: either be filled with dread about the outcome, or get angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As time has gone on, I realized that I, like maybe almost everyone, am not good at dealing with anxiety in positive ways. I first became aware of this maybe 8 years ago, on my first cross-country drive alone, when nothing went wrong at all, yet I was filled with dread about what &lt;em&gt;might&lt;/em&gt; go wrong for almost the entire trip. This is the best way I can explain the kind of anxiety that I seem prone to: always trying to forecast what may or may not happen and pre-empt it. The problem is my pre-empting usually means worrying—and worrying destroys the experience of whatever is &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, no one can say what may or may not happen. Every moment is a dice roll as to what will turn up. About a month ago I finished reading a book called &lt;em&gt;The Wisdom of Insecurity&lt;/em&gt;. That book, by Alan Watts, states that we live in not &lt;em&gt;an&lt;/em&gt; age of anxiety but &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; age of anxiety—and this book was written decades ago, when people may have been less anxious than they are now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason, Watts posits, that we are so anxious is because we are constantly trying to tie the water of life into neat little paper packages. This metaphor resounded with me because of my Body of Water project, and also because of its truthfulness. Water &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; like life, in the metaphorical sense—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The whole problem of existence&lt;br&gt;
is that we are are like a river, but not&lt;br&gt;
minds always flowing&lt;br&gt;
restless, unable to stop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trying to stop, or flow&lt;br&gt;
never gets the same place&lt;br&gt;
to go anywhere else.&lt;br&gt;
Making blockages, breaking&lt;br&gt;
the going still going.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://write.as/bodyofwater&#34;&gt;A Body of Water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this poem long before I read Watts&amp;rsquo; book. Yet reading his book about insecurity deepened my own understanding of what I was trying to say in that poem. Life flows along in ways no one can control. Yet it seems most of what I have been taught about &amp;ldquo;how to live&amp;rdquo; has been about control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watts goes on—since life is uncontrollable, the only realistic act is a kind of surrender to or focus on the present moment. The present is the only moment we really have. It&amp;rsquo;s strange to &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; realize this—that Past is a memory, and Future is  a story. And whether we think about the future or the past, we are doing so in the present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how does the present moment relate to anxiety? Thusly: if this moment right now—of sitting at the birchwood breakfast table, typing in the morning light, with the stove heating water in a steel pot, and the cool air flowing in through the window—is all I have, then what I choose to pay attention to, in this moment and the next, becomes my entire life. Life ceases to be about some imagined future or remembered past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore your reaction to this moment can be called a produced experience, and that reaction/experience can be colored in uncountable ways. It turns out that this produced experience, whether it be of anxiety, happiness, anger, etc is all that we really have. It&amp;rsquo;s the experience of this very moment. Since that is the case, whether we have an anxious or non-anxious experience seems to be up to us. Yet the weight of habit and conditioning compels us to not be able to control our produced experience (our reaction) to the given experience (the set of circumstances) of this moment. So we may react &amp;ldquo;badly&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;well&amp;rdquo;, yet these reactions &amp;ldquo;never get the same place/to go anywhere else&amp;rdquo;. We are still firmly stuck in our experience, whether we are approaching it in &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bad&amp;rdquo; ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where I get confused, yet the idea of &amp;ldquo;not controlling&amp;rdquo; the experience seems important. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to go down the rabbit hole of &amp;ldquo;free will&amp;rdquo; vs &amp;ldquo;divine plan&amp;rdquo; and/or the existence of a &amp;ldquo;self&amp;rdquo; (read Watts&amp;rsquo; book). So the only thing I can say is that habituating yourself to a different produced experience during the given experience is the only way forward to being different, to getting that same place/person to go somewhere or be someone else. The only way to do this is not to be lost in the past or future, regret or anxiety, and to be aware of the given experience of this moment, and your reaction to it. That&amp;rsquo;s really the only hope to overcoming past habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeing things this way has helped me get a hold on my anxiety issues, maybe more than ever before. Anxiety is a type of fear, which meticulous planning and forecasting is supposed to prevent. Fear is one of the most powerful forces in the world. So, to be unafraid is to not be controlled by circumstance, to not be controlled by fear when plans inevitably go awry. This is a very grounded way to live, and really the only clear way as far as I can reason. I hope that with more practice I can become less anxious and more able to live in the present—in the stream of the water of life, rather than trying to control it and getting upset when it collapses the sides of my paper box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-May/2-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ba6qkzkpSXQ&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>May 1, 2020</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/may-1-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 06:32:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/may-1-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I wanted to share a few photos from the old times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in those days when I lived in a place with a community of people around, and in a place that felt like home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When rent was $250 a month, and I got all the free vegetables I ever wanted from the co-op where I worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I used to have film cameras, and spend the days between work and college wandering alleys finding moments of beauty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know, the good old days. Everyone had them once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not to say these days aren&amp;rsquo;t good and old either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always find the good old days when I take my time and walk places. They still lurk around rusting old mailboxes and rough cut tree stumps. And around the edges of strange young lizards basking on the concrete on hot days. And nowadays I know a few more things, like what matters to me, and what I want to do most times. Yet the old friend &amp;ldquo;confusion&amp;rdquo; often creeps in, and anxiety too. (Confusion is a pale old man with a five panel hat named &amp;ldquo;pi-kun&amp;rdquo; who sits endlessly at a diner late into the night. But these days I don&amp;rsquo;t have much I want to prove, or anything particularly to achieve. You may say I left lots of ideas I used to have back in those same old days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-may/CJ-1MAY20-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-may/CJ-1MAY20-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-may/CJ-1MAY20-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2020-may/CJ-1MAY20-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 30, 2020</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/april-30-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 09:01:56 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/april-30-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I saw a man playing trumpet for an hour over background jazz music&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a woman juggling, and answering every question&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw birds collect in the backyard, drinking water three times a day, arguing about who goes first&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a cat sleeping on a stack of pillows&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw steam rise from morning tea&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw ineffable feelings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw the color of roast hazelnuts when I took them out of the oven&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw people turning inward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw people helping one another&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw beyond the surface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw shadows in the dark&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw light changing in the morning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also saw the days growing longer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw photos of my friends farming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw people typing and working&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw a man back hoeing in a dry river alone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw clear water flowing over yellowish rocks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw aspens turning green&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also saw myself in a mirror one day&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked into my eyes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were darker than I remembered&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They reflected some light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and absorbed some light&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and also let light in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 29, 2020</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/april-29-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 06:59:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/april-29-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/prcvl/nicolas-jaar-april161900gmt&#34;&gt;Music For You To Listen To While You Read&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking across valleys&lt;br&gt;
then down to rivers.&lt;br&gt;
So much space to choose from&lt;br&gt;
yet a tiny trail threads through the middle.&lt;br&gt;
A distant mountain, thirty miles away&lt;br&gt;
looks like it can be touched.&lt;br&gt;
Walking toward it for three days&lt;br&gt;
it only grows larger.&lt;br&gt;
Standing on it, like an ant on a house.&lt;br&gt;
Chipped bones from reindeer&lt;br&gt;
lay beside granite rocks—&lt;br&gt;
Twinflower blooming pinkly in dark clefts—&lt;br&gt;
a place to sleep.&lt;br&gt;
Cloudberries to eat&lt;br&gt;
cold water to drink.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to write anymore, I look into my bones. I spoke recently about the writing bone, but this is a different kind of bone.  A new bone, and old bone. Bones meaning things that hold us up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When one doesn&amp;rsquo;t notice their bones, one feels weightless. The bones attach to ligaments, and then to muscles, which keep it all moving. You can control your body with just your mind. Look, my fingers are typing out this unphysical series of thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bones are made of minerals. Do bones grow and change?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun this morning first landed on the tawny chamisatops. Not all people like the smell of that bush, but I do. Cattle around here ate all the sagebrush. So now there&amp;rsquo;s only chamisa left. Sage brush dies after a fire because it spreads by seed. So there has to be a new crop to blow seed to where it was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many sounds, thoughts, feelings—all occurring in a vast expanse. This expanse stretches from the great bone in the sky to the red blood of the ground and then spreads out in who knows how many directions. In the center of this space is a warm white sphere. This sphere some call your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April 27, 2020</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/april-27-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 08:21:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/april-27-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ten days of spring cold kept me indoors;&lt;br&gt;
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know willows were budding in the village.&lt;br&gt;
In the frozen valley, a stream gurgles faintly;&lt;br&gt;
sheets of green hide burnt stubble in the fields.&lt;br&gt;
A few acres of poor land hold me here;&lt;br&gt;
warming half a jug of cloudy wine, I wait for you.&lt;br&gt;
A year ago today I crossed the mountain pass -&lt;br&gt;
fine rain on plum flowers nearly broke my spirit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Su Tung-p&amp;rsquo;o&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lodgepole Forest</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/lodgepole-forest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 07:25:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/lodgepole-forest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Walking in the dry forest&lt;br&gt;
single note of a grey bird.&lt;br&gt;
Peel up some bark&lt;br&gt;
use it for a seat&lt;br&gt;
lay down later same place to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Light rain in morning.&lt;br&gt;
Wake under a log.&lt;br&gt;
Open eyes to forest floor&lt;br&gt;
scent of fresh mushrooms&lt;br&gt;
growing from what has died.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Birds single song.&lt;br&gt;
Walking through lodgepole.&lt;br&gt;
Mind running like an endless river.&lt;br&gt;
The morning and the day so near.&lt;br&gt;
Evening so far away.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Hiking New Mexico</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/light-hiking-new-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 07:11:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/light-hiking-new-mexico/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-20APR20-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-20APR20-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-20APR20-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-20APR20-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-20APR20-6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up in the high valleys of the Sangre de Cristo mountains, the snow has begun to melt. Patches of snow remain below the aspen groves, or on northern slopes. High up, around 9,500 feet, the snow is still deep. Near Agua Piedra (rock water) I found a closed trail headed up to a valley. We parked the truck down the road, and walked past closed summer cabins to the beginning. A creek ran quickly to the left. It ran through a dry, mixed forest of ponderosa, white fir, and spruce. The forest of Northern New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost nothing was green yet. But sapsuckers and woodpeckers screamed and hammered on dead trunks. Red squirrels chided from spruce boughs. My left arm went totally numb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was hiking with a 30L frameless pack. But to the back was strapped a tomahawk. And a bahco laplander saw. These two extra items, along with the steep grade, pulled my back backwards toward the earth, compressing the brachial plexus of my left side. This resulted in a pins and needles feeling in my hands, which quickly gave way to stiffness and pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After ceaselessly adjusting the pack, and wondering aloud with Anna why the trail was marked closed (we counted 3 minor downed trees), we hit flat ground. Then the valley opened up before us. Elk sign was everywhere. Wild flowers, that looked like trillium, were just beginning to grow. But the grass in the valley was laid flat and golden by the snow that had so recently melted. And an old wrecked cabin stood at the edge, roof and half its timbers gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahead of us Bear Hill (cerro del oso) loomed, covered in aspen and rocky mountain doug fir. We crossed the narrow stream through a thicket of alders and set up camp amongst ground that had not been camped on in years. The path through the meadow, though clear and easy, was growing in. Pocket gophers heaved dirt mounds in the center of the trail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trees, huge for this dry state, loomed on the eastern side of the meadow. The sun would rise there. We went to the west side, a few tens of feet above valley bottom, amidst a grove of aspen, above where the cold air would settle during the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The small clearing where we stayed was the domain of elk. Rubbings on trees showed where they worked the velvet off their antlers last summer. Small paths crossing the stream showed the best way to walk. Nibbled aspen tops showed what they had been eating. A rumbling and crackling, and then thumping into the distance along the slope near sundown showed we were in their way. We slept all night long by the stream, and heard two owls hooting early in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along the edge of the little clearing a spruce had died and fallen. Its branches were sticking into the air. I used my saw and tomahawk to cut and split several. They were so dry they lit like a candle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the hours passed in the meadow, I looked around at the trees and grass. The ground was lumpy from years of gopher work. There was downed wood everywhere. It was easy to tell that no human had stayed here for a long time, or if they had they had left no trace. Due to unmarked nature of the trail, and the closed sign, I wondered how long it had been, since deer and elk alone had walked here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I trimmed dead branches from the base of a living doug fir, to clean the trunk and hang my pack there. I cut and sawed branches of aspen, and used a rotting one as a sawhorse. I bucked and piled and lit the wood, and boiled creek water for hot spruce needle tea. By using the land, with the small knowledge I had, I made it less fire prone, and better for humans like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet the shaping and moving of such small things, in such a tiny quiet place, stuck in my mind and troubled me. Are we born to do such things, is our use only a use of such space? I think that we can contribute more than we take. We can do crazy things like move beavers to places they once lived. They fix the rivers the cows destroyed, and put thousands of gallons into reservoirs. In a single day a beaver can fix what cows took ten years to desecrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So with our knowing eye we can grow food for more than us, and make watering places for birds. We can use the land in a way that helps, and not only in ways that harm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next morning I donned my wool sweater against the chill. I cut green willow to size and made a rack for bacon above our fire. The smoke mingled with the salt and fat. We ate the bacon hot and crispy with green chiles grown down south in the hatch valley.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 08:51:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maybe the important thing to remember about love is when it is held at a distance, examined, it may seem sentimental, cliché, impractical, useless, or mysterious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when love is experienced, it seems to be the only true reality, the only real choice one could make, or at least the best choice—it seems to clarify everything and fill the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all for today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Hudson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Same Day</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-same-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 10:18:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-same-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-16APR20-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The red woven towel hangs limply from the oven.&lt;br&gt;
I have already used it twice to dry my hands today.&lt;br&gt;
The wind&lt;br&gt;
outside&lt;br&gt;
moves new leaves of bushes.&lt;br&gt;
The ants have begun to build tunnels.&lt;br&gt;
A metal shack&lt;br&gt;
by the beat up street&lt;br&gt;
has a padlock I have never tried to open.&lt;br&gt;
The lock hangs from a handle that is rusting off.&lt;br&gt;
The apricot tree nearby&lt;br&gt;
has never been pruned.&lt;br&gt;
Yet every year it produces new fruit.&lt;br&gt;
Cars still pass&lt;br&gt;
on Agua Fria street.&lt;br&gt;
The sun still rises
and wakes me up.&lt;br&gt;
I feel confused about how I feel&lt;br&gt;
when each day is the same.&lt;br&gt;
This endless cycle of waking&lt;br&gt;
and sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sun in the Morning</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-sun-in-the-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 08:10:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-sun-in-the-morning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-15APR-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-15APR-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-15APR-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-15APR-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-15APR-6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sun rises in the morning above the northern wall of the alley. The window above my shikibuton looks out onto Oregon Grape plants that now have flowers. Bees and other insects come to the flowers for the nectar. The flowers are bright yellow, the same color as the core of the plant under the bark. The plant contains berberine, which makes it incredibly bitter. The flowers become fat, deep purple berries that are both sweet and bitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plant itself can be used to treat psoriasis. Berberine is strongly anti-bacterial and anti-inflammatory. The root, dried and powdered, can be used directly on wounds to prevent infection, or taken orally for food poisoning. A tea of the roots/bark works as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bitterness itself is good for digestion. Bitter flavor increases saliva production and other gastric juices, and even the production of hormones that stimulate the gall bladder (where bile is stored) and the pancreas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The color of the flowers of the spiky Oregon Grape is really the same color as the sunlight. The bitter, spiky nature of the plant is interesting to encounter.  Bitterness is restorative, though unpleasant in the process. Just like certain things in life. The deep green glossy leaves shelter small birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today the color of the sunlight is white. The sky is blue. I listened to Margaret Atwood speak yesterday about keeping squirrels from living in her roof by putting hot pepper into where they lived. Then she said: that if you have a place to stay, and you know how to get food, you really have all you need. You&amp;rsquo;re OK. She said many people who are younger (she is 80) worry that life has changed and that they won&amp;rsquo;t be able to do the things they had planned anymore. But as an old person, her perspective is different. She has lived through many calamities, and now has less life to look forward to than life she lived. So her perspective is different. Yet it&amp;rsquo;s like an old tree vs a young one. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say that, despite the wisdom of her perspective, the two perspectives, of looking forward, and looking backward, are hard to reconcile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also heard someone say recently that there is no running away from your demons anymore. Indeed, there is little to distract from things. I often talk about the root of the bone, which is a funny phrase. I hope for everyone that they get closer to the root of the bone. It&amp;rsquo;s spring and everyone should be together and doing things. Yet we are not. So it&amp;rsquo;s root of the bone time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hear bears are wandering freely in Yosemite because there aren&amp;rsquo;t millions of people there anymore. I wonder what flowers are blooming there. I wonder if there will be more flowers in such places than we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in years?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Hudson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worries</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 08:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/worries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laying on my back&lt;br&gt;
My back begins to warm&lt;br&gt;
The soft cushion of the bed&lt;br&gt;
I have no plans&lt;br&gt;
Only worries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember an ivory bear&lt;br&gt;
With a turquoise arrowhead tied to it&amp;rsquo;s back&lt;br&gt;
That I used to keep in a hidden wooden box&lt;br&gt;
Where I used to keep my worries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Korma</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coconut-korma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 14:43:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coconut-korma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have found this deceptively simple, vegan curry recipe to be just as delicious as one made with a masala. The individual flavors (garlic, ginger, cloves, cardamom) stand out more instead of getting lost in a cacophony of spices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;INGREDIENTS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• 6&lt;/strong&gt; cloves&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 8&lt;/strong&gt; cardamom pods&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 1 tbsp&lt;/strong&gt; Kashmiri chile powder, OR Korean chile powder OR whatever you have (optional)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 1&lt;/strong&gt; head garlic, peeled and ground to a paste, or finely chopped (&lt;strong&gt;Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; shake cloves in a jar for 2 minutes or until skins loosen)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 2.5 inches&lt;/strong&gt; of ginger root, ground to a paste or chopped finely&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• ½&lt;/strong&gt; red or yellow onion, sliced thinly into half moons&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 1 can&lt;/strong&gt; (13.5 oz) unsweetened coconut milk&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• ¼ cup&lt;/strong&gt; salty vegetable stock, OR &lt;strong&gt;1 tbsp&lt;/strong&gt; miso paste diluted with &lt;strong&gt;¼ cup&lt;/strong&gt; water&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 1 tbsp&lt;/strong&gt; lime juice, or &lt;strong&gt;3 tbsp&lt;/strong&gt; tomato sauce/chopped tomatoes&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;•&lt;/strong&gt; neutral oil, such as grapeseed or vegetable.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;•&lt;/strong&gt; Salt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vegetable--meat-options&#34;&gt;VEGETABLE / MEAT OPTIONS&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;• 3 large&lt;/strong&gt; carrots, cut into bite-sized pieces &lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;• 3 medium&lt;/strong&gt; yukon gold potatoes, peeled and cut into bite sized pieces &lt;strong&gt;OR&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;•  1.5 lbs&lt;/strong&gt; Chicken (white or dark meat, preferably with skin) cut into bite sized pieces&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; you can also do a mix of the above, or even add &lt;strong&gt;½ cup&lt;/strong&gt; frozen peas to the carrots and/or potatoes (which I like to do).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;METHOD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dry roast cardamom and cloves in a large sauté pan over medium heat until fragrant and popping. Be careful not to brown them! Add enough oil cover the pan to 1cm, turn heat to medium-high, then add the garlic and ginger, frying for two minutes. Add the onions, and fry for one minute more with a good pinch of salt. Then add the vegetable/meat of your choice (if using frozen peas, add them after the coconut milk). Fry for another two minutes, then pour in the coconut milk and stock/miso and add the chile powder. Allow the sauce to simmer, then reduce heat to medium-low. Add lime juice or tomatoes, then simmer for about 12 minutes or until sauce has thickened, checking meat and/or vegetables for doneness. Adjust salt to taste, and serve with freshly cooked rice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Is a Habit</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/busy-is-a-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 07:52:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/busy-is-a-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-10APR20-2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few excerpts from &lt;a href=&#34;http://theabundanceofless.com&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Abundance of Less&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt; by Andy Couturier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Maybe to someone else this would be terrible. But to me, I spent fifteen years traveling, and I was so satisfied doing that, when I came to this village I could live like this—&amp;rdquo; He looks around [at the barn he converted to a home] with a deeply contented and thankful expression—&amp;ldquo;I felt like I pulled off something terrific. When I quit my job, I worried so much that my life would be terrible when I got old. And it turned out this good!&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside, the snow has turned to rain, and with it&amp;rsquo;s gentle sounds on the roof Nakamura lays out some old futons for me to sleep on. As my body begins to warm up the bedclothes, the familiar tranquility of the Japanese countryside settles over me again, and, with the sounds of the river below and the rain falling on the roof, I drift off to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the morning, when I awake, Nakamura is already up and making breakfast. Out the windows, mists are gathering and drifting on the dark green cedar forest across the rainy valley, looking like nothing so much as an old Chinese ink painting. On the cookstove, Nakamura is making some sticky bread muffins in a set of stacked bamboo steamers over a wok full of boiling water. The crackle of kindling reminds me again of Nakamura&amp;rsquo;s wood-centered life. At the table he is cutting updates and other dried fruits to add to our sampa, the Tibetan staple food made from toasted barley flour,  a chunk of butter, and in Nakamura&amp;rsquo;s case, Awa &lt;em&gt;bancha&lt;/em&gt; tea, all of which is then mixed into a paste. It&amp;rsquo;s not what I usually have for breakfast, but it&amp;rsquo;s warm and tasty, and the dried fruit makes the meal particularly delicious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I look outside, and it seems like it might just keep raining all day. I ask Nakamura what he usually does on days like today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sometimes I carve woodblocks, or read, but mostly, when I have nothing to just stare into the fire.&amp;rdquo; he says his face showing an expression of a person in the movement of flames flickering their mesmerizing dance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I raise my eyebrows, and then he says with a smile, &amp;ldquo;Doing nothing all day- it&amp;rsquo;s difficult at first. Being busy is a habit, and a hard one to break.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But then I think that perhaps such a life—very little production, very little consumption—might be an important part of the solution to the world ecological crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we look out at the clouds on the far mountains, I ask Nakamura: &amp;ldquo;Do you feel that you are living a life of luxury?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Luxury? No, not luxury. It&amp;rsquo;s an ordinary life. But I do feel an abundance, a sense of plenty. A hundred years ago I would not have been able to choose what kind of life to live. I feel very lucky to be living in this age.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;em&gt;The Abundance of Less. Lessons in Simple Living from Rural Japan&lt;/em&gt; by Andy Courtier. From the chapter &amp;ldquo;A Woodblock Craftsman Discovers Hand Work and the Heart&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand Dune Camp</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/sand-dune-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:45:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/sand-dune-camp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wide emptiness.&lt;br&gt;
Spaceless nothingness.&lt;br&gt;
Dust              &lt;br&gt;
from millions of years&lt;br&gt;
piled up high.&lt;br&gt;
Mountains loom&lt;br&gt;
but aren&amp;rsquo;t that steep.&lt;br&gt;
Legs feel tired from hours of sand.&lt;br&gt;
Spots of water in the dunes &lt;br&gt;
crooked cottonwoods&lt;br&gt;
and an owl.&lt;br&gt;
Fire of juniper twigs&lt;br&gt;
above a dry pond.&lt;br&gt;
All opens up&lt;br&gt;
then closes in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked so far&lt;br&gt;
to get right here.&lt;br&gt;
Dry creek bed&lt;br&gt;
The night wind—&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shadow moves&lt;br&gt;
sand plants&lt;br&gt;
blown by wind&lt;br&gt;
making circles&lt;br&gt;
in the sand.&lt;br&gt;
Or was it a hand&lt;br&gt;
that drew them?&lt;br&gt;
A shadow moves &lt;br&gt;
amidst the dunes&lt;br&gt;
Then merges into deep&lt;br&gt;
dune sand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-9APR20-11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come Together</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/come-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 06:17:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/come-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone on earth has had an argument with another person. During the argument, when emotions are high, it&amp;rsquo;s often really hard to recognize the other person as human. All kinds of bad words and names come to mind. Maybe not everyone feels this way during arguments, but I know that I have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To ameliorate the impact of arguments, I came up with an idea of agreements, which I think I first encountered talking with my mom, when we were talking about a book called &lt;em&gt;The Four Agreements&lt;/em&gt; by Don Miguel Ruiz. His four agreements are these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-be-impeccable-with-your-word&#34;&gt;1. Be Impeccable With Your Word&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-dont-take-anything-personally&#34;&gt;2. Don&amp;rsquo;t Take Anything Personally&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-dont-make-assumptions&#34;&gt;3. Don&amp;rsquo;t Make Assumptions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-always-do-your-best&#34;&gt;4. Always Do Your Best&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keeping all of these agreements all the time seems impossible. At least I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to keep them. I think that holding oneself to an unrealistic standard can create friction within. So to simplify these few agreements, and make them more realistic for myself, I have  developed just two of my own in dealing with conflict —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not argue in bad faith.&lt;/strong&gt; Argue with civility. This means: do not insult or personally attack someone, or try to prove that they are inherently bad. Argue the &lt;strong&gt;issue&lt;/strong&gt; at hand, not the goodness or badness of the person. An important phrase here is ad hominem, &amp;ldquo;to the person&amp;rdquo;, which in fancy terms is a fallacy (an unsound argument). It means mistaking the act for the person. Often this kind of argument occurs over beliefs like religion or politics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try my best to help the relationship survive.&lt;/strong&gt; This does not mean the relationship has to stay the same, but that civility, kindness, care, and regard for one another are maintained, even if the parties go their separate ways. Sometimes a relationship can fully survive, and continue on as it was, and sometimes it changes. This depends on the depth of the relationship, and the seriousness of the argument.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read an article yesterday morning, after I wrote about cookies, about how the UK asked for volunteers to help vulnerable Britons, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2020/04/07/world/europe/coronavirus-volunteers-uk.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=Spotlight&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&#34;&gt;more than 750,000 people signed up.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, Kate Sellars was organizing a James Bond getaway for her wealthy clients, in which they would have been flown by helicopter to Monte Carlo for a preview of the latest Bond movie, a glittering party with cast members and, for each guest, an Aston Martin gassed up and ready to drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, Ms. Sellars lugged two bags of groceries from her local supermarket to the front step of Garth D’lima, a 73-year-old retired accountant who is marooned inside his house as the coronavirus sweeps London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It’s just heartbreaking not to be able to help him carry his groceries up the stairs,” she said, as she waved at Mr. D’lima from his front gate. “We can’t go into people’s houses because that would put them at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is remarkable journalism, and incredibly important in these times. The first paragraph paints a picture of a lavish, out-of-touch person. The second nukes that opinion. The third brought me to tears.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also proves the uselessness of ad hominem arguments, as it shows people are not defined by one action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“During the Brexit debate, people used to say what we really need is a common enemy — and now we’ve got it,” said David Goodhart, a writer whose last book, “The Road to Somewhere,” explored the divide in British society between the rooted and the rootless. “Except this is an invisible enemy.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we are all people. Yes, we all have our idiosyncrasies. But the sharing of our common humanity is our most powerful asset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;When I speak of ‘basic human feeling’, I refer to the capacity we all have to empathize with one another. This is what enables us to enter into the pain of others and, to some extent, participate in the pain of others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our innate capacity for empathy is the source of that most precious of all human qualities, which in Tibetan we call &lt;em&gt;nyingjé&lt;/em&gt;. The term &lt;em&gt;nyingjé&lt;/em&gt; has a wealth of meaning that includes: love, affection, kindness, gentleness, generosity of spirit, and warm-heartedness. &lt;strong&gt;It does not imply pity; on the contrary, &lt;em&gt;nyingjé&lt;/em&gt; denotes a feeling of connection with others.&lt;/strong&gt; Also, it belongs to that category of emotions which have a more developed cognitive component. So we can understand &lt;em&gt;nyingjé&lt;/em&gt; as a combination of empathy and reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can think of empathy as the characteristic of a very warm-hearted or well-meaning person; reason as that of someone who is very practical (and truly intelligent and wise). When the two are put together, the combination is highly effective.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;— HHDL, Ethics for the New Millenium&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading about The UK&amp;rsquo;s strategy of recruiting willing volunteers (they put out a call for 250,000 and got the aforementioned 750,000 applicants) is exactly the story we all need to hear right now. I think it is easy to want to slay dragons. It&amp;rsquo;s harder to think that helping your 70 your old neighbor matters. But you know who it helps? Your 70 year old neighbor. And I think it helps you, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortbread Cookies</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shortbread-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 07:41:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shortbread-cookies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the morning I make tea. And lately I have been accompanying it with a single shortbread cookie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time I resisted making delicious cookies, because the problem of sugar. But I found if I make less delicious cookies, since they are less delicious, they don&amp;rsquo;t scratch the cookie itch very well, so I end up eating more of them—which pretty much defeats the purpose of making &amp;ldquo;more healthy&amp;rdquo; cookies. :( So thanks to Anna&amp;rsquo;s find of this great recipe, I&amp;rsquo;ve resorted to making cookies that are really too good. And somehow limiting myself to eating just two a day, since they really scratch the cookie itch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;INGREDIENTS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1 cup plus 2 tablespoons&lt;/strong&gt; (9 ounces or 255 grams) room temperature salted butter (if not using salted butter, add ¾ tsp salt)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 3/4 cup&lt;/strong&gt; (150 grams) sugar (brown, or light brown)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1 teaspoon&lt;/strong&gt; (5 ml) vanilla extract&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 2 ¼ cups&lt;/strong&gt; (295 grams) all-purpose flour&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 6 ounces&lt;/strong&gt; (170 grams) semi- or bittersweet dark chocolate, chopped (you want chunks, not thin shards of chocolate)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1&lt;/strong&gt; large egg (optional)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘&lt;/strong&gt; Demerara, turbinado, raw, or sanding sugar, for rolling (optional)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘&lt;/strong&gt; Flaky sea salt for sprinkling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;METHOD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beat the butter, sugar, and vanilla with a metal spoon or fork until light and fluffy, scraping down bowl as needed. (&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; if you use a mixer, the butter must be cold and cut into small pieces. But it&amp;rsquo;s easy enough to beat warm butter with a fork IMO). Add flour, and mix until just combined. Add chocolate chunks, mix just until incorporated. Mixture will be crumbly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divide dough evenly between two sheets of parchment paper, waxed paper, reusable wax cloths, or plastic wrap and use your hands to form the dough halves into logs about 2 to 2 1/4 inches in diameter. Chill until totally firm in freezer (30 min) or fridge (~2 hours).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you’re ready to bake, heat  oven to 350°F. Line one or two large baking sheets with parchment paper, or silpat if you have one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optional:&lt;/strong&gt; Lightly beat the egg and open up your chilled cookies logs to brush it over the sides. Sprinkle the coarse sugar on the open paper or plastic wrap and roll the logs into it, coating them. (Honestly, these cookies are cookielike enough without egg coated candied edges!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using a sharp serrated knife, cut logs into 1/2-inch thick rounds. You’re going to hit some chocolate chunks, so saw gently, squeezing the cookie to keep it from breaking if needed. Arrange slices on prepared sheets one inch apart (they don’t spread much) and sprinkle each with a few flakes of salt. Bake for 12 to 15 minutes, or until the edges are just beginning to get golden brown. People always talk about wire cooling racks, but I don&amp;rsquo;t own one—I just let the cookies cool on a room temperature sheet or plate. Voila!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frost&#39;s Old Woods</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/frosts-old-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 06:19:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/frosts-old-woods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took a break from writing over the weekend—not because I had nothing to write, but because resting the writing bone seemed like a good idea. But now that I try to write again I feel like I lost the thread I had found. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s that nothing has changed from where I was on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend I watched the lizards and birds outside in the sun. I made chaga tea over a twig stove from a chaga conk I found in Robert Frost&amp;rsquo;s old stomping grounds. I don&amp;rsquo;t often use the chaga from that conk, it&amp;rsquo;s more of a keepsake, but I guess one day I will use it all eventually. When I found the chaga, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know I was walking in Frost&amp;rsquo;s old woods until I saw a sign about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was there, in Frost&amp;rsquo;s old woods, all the open hay meadows had filled in with meadowsweet. It was summer, in fact the day after my birthday, which I had spent alone in Eastern Vermont camped in a forest. I was running away from something terrible, that I had to go back to after this brief sojourn. But for those few days, I managed to forget about all the pain and strangeness I had to return to, though they cast a shadow on my mind, and even though I love sleeping in a tent at night, I didn&amp;rsquo;t sleep well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed the meadows near Frost&amp;rsquo;s old woods were on their way to becoming forest again. And there were other meadows nearby, that had not been filled in by brush and small trees, that were still cut once every few years. They were dense with hundreds of wildflowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a big deal writing retreat near Frosts Woods just a little further up the valley, called Bread Loaf I think. And there were hundreds of cars in a giant lot filling the grounds in front of the old farm buildings that people now wrote and slept in. I wandered around the grounds, and probably could have walked right into the workshop classes if I had wanted to. In the winter Bread Loaf turns into a nordic skiing center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Frost&amp;rsquo;s old woods everything was going wild again. Yet just down the road, there was the big expensive hard-to-get-into retreat center, filled with people trying to&amp;hellip; what? I sit here, trying to make sense of each moment, and then turn it into words. Maybe that&amp;rsquo;s what they are doing too. Yet, the trees and plants that grow in those overgrown meadows, that even now are probably leafing out, they just grow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Years of Growth</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/three-years-of-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 05:38:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/three-years-of-growth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trackless trackless mountain cloud&lt;br&gt;
what do I ask to be?&lt;br&gt;
To be you, to be you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming—going into nothing&lt;br&gt;
what do I ask to see?&lt;br&gt;
To see you, to see you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trackless trackless mountain path&lt;br&gt;
where do I ask to go?&lt;br&gt;
To find you, to find you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trackless trackless meadow of flowers&lt;br&gt;
What do I ask of you?&lt;br&gt;
To believe you.&lt;br&gt;
To believe you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it ever feel, to you, like you are doing what you were made to do? I wonder if everyone has some feeling like that, at some point in their life. It comes in and out like baconfry static on the radio, for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the idealized life is often said to be &amp;ldquo;in balance&amp;rdquo;—work-life balance, family balance, relationship balance, or balancing your checkbook (just kidding). Maybe a life that feels aligned is one of balance? Yet, for me, those moments where I feel properly &amp;ldquo;in the flow&amp;rdquo; aren&amp;rsquo;t continuous. Which leaves me wanting them when they are gone, which, in a way, creates imbalance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read recently that the idea of balance in the natural world is actually misguided. The natural world is a chaotic series of successions. A forest burns and fireweed sprouts. Aspens, their roots underground and safe from fire, send up shoots in every direction, eventually shading out the fireweed and almost anything else. In fifty to a hundred years the aspens grow huge and die and fall, just in time for the seedlings of fir and pine and hemlock, which grew from seeds brought there and cached by birds and mammals, to rocket skyward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of balance, this unattainable thing (if we&amp;rsquo;re being honest), is applied to human lives, since it exists in nature, right? What if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist in nature, what then? Maybe our lives are actually not meant to be balanced, and the attempt to seek some perfect balance is impossible. It makes us chase that &amp;ldquo;in the flow&amp;rdquo; feeling, which sets up life to be a series of ups and downs. Life is and always was and always will be a series of unpredictable events. There is no perpetual balance within uncertainty. Maybe life is more like an infinite act of rebalancing, or, you could say, flowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet nature functions well, and we do too. Nature has us beat in that it does not worry about balance. It just expresses, in all its mystery, the breath of life. And I feel myself, myself, what I am made to do, if I am honest, is to do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Anna and I drove the truck up the mountain to a creekside trail we found a year ago. We went down it together, amazed at the colors and motion of butterflies that seemed to spontaneously appear in the sunlight. The aspen trunks were white and snow lay in crevices along the path. We wound down to the river and walked along it for a while, then found a meadow. I set up my tent, just for fun, and used a small camp axe to buck some wood for whoever would have a fire there next. Anna  laid in the sun, or watched the river flow by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over Anna&amp;rsquo;s chest and down the left side of her body hung a massive, thick braid. I picked up the end of it. &amp;ldquo;Remember biking the road up to Big Bear?&amp;rdquo; I asked. &amp;ldquo;Yeah, I was just looking at photos from then&amp;rdquo;, she said, &amp;ldquo;and three years ago we did that ride. After we got back I went up to Washington and stayed with Brit and Sam and then went to my mom&amp;rsquo;s house and cut off all my hair.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;Three years of growth,&amp;rdquo; I said pulling lightly at her thick braid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To realize three years had passed since then felt funny and sad at the same time. Because, mostly, this flow of experiences we name Life doesn&amp;rsquo;t always flow easily or clearly. The pain of the turns can be acute. And yet, they all flow together somewhere, and get bunched up in memory, and then you can sit on a rock in the spring sun in the mountains and think about all the times when things weren&amp;rsquo;t so good, and the times also when they were good, and then come back to the time right now—which is &lt;em&gt;really all the time we have.&lt;/em&gt; And it&amp;rsquo;s strange to think of, that there is a physical representation of all that time that hangs beautiful and thick from Anna&amp;rsquo;s head—of a thousand thousand strands braided together—of three years of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronajournal - Cats &amp; Car Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 07:40:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been doing pushups lately. But my schedule is erratic. I rarely know when I will do a pushup. Sometimes I do them in the morning before I take my dogbone loop run through the dry neighborhoods. Sometimes at night just before bed. There are lots of times when I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do them, but I do them anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I write now I can hear birds outside in the chamisa, which is also called rabbitbrush. Some people really don&amp;rsquo;t like the scent of rabbitbrush, but I tend to like it for some reason. The birds live in it as it provides good cover from the neighborhood cats. Did you know domestic cats kill billions of small mammals and birds every year? They are single-pawedly implicated in the extinction of speceies in some places, like islands. If you ever wonder why there are less birds year after year—because, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed, there are—blame the cats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning my hands are cold and I haven&amp;rsquo;t moved from the red futon that I write on sometimes. I first meditated for a while but couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop thinking about all the aspects of my car that need to be fixed still before we leave Santa Fe. So far I have replaced the thermostat, the bottom radiator hose, the rear differential fluid, about 20 feet of vaccuum line, the PCV valve, the radiator cap. I sealed the exhaust with muffler weld and also used some room temperature vulcanizing silicone to fix a tiny tear that developed in the stupid brand new 900-dollar-job CV boot. Sorry if that&amp;rsquo;s boring to hear, because a year ago I also wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have known what almost any of that was. But if you buy a 1991 Isuzu Pickup off craigslist, even if it only has 64,000 miles on it (like this one) you better know how to replace a lot of stuff fast or you&amp;rsquo;re gonna run up a big bill at the mechanic. The only work that really is left to do is the valve cover gasket and maybe a fuel line that leaks randomly every 6 months. Oh, and the front brakes. Which I&amp;rsquo;ll leave to a mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have managed to spend this entire morning hacking away at this website, which I built more or less from scratch a year ago. Coding is a lot like auto maintainence actually. One tries things and turns it back on, and if it sounds good, I guess it is done right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The light keeps changing every day. The days are longer, but we are inside. It seems trails are shutting down all over the country. I wonder if animals are feeling restful with less people around. It&amp;rsquo;s great of humans to go outdoors, to own cars, cats, and all these things. But man, it sure takes a tax on the earth in the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - We Are All A Part</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-1APR20-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Corona Journal - Hudson Gardner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-1APR20-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Corona Journal - Hudson Gardner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/CJ-1APR20-3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Corona Journal - Hudson Gardner&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Corona virus,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to Kenya. A few things you should know. Here we don&amp;rsquo;t die of flu, don&amp;rsquo;t be suprised if you fail to succeed. Usishangae [don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised], everything fails in Kenya.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are not very excited to host you around, no offence but locusts arrived way earlier than you and first come first served, unless utoe kitu kidogo then you can skip the queue of our attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also cannot afford to pay you too much attention because we really really broke. Incase you haven&amp;rsquo;t heard our economy&amp;hellip;. is in the toilet. Shh&amp;hellip;whisper please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t expect us to fight for sanitizers and tissue paper like the westerners, we shit and wipe with bush leaves. We are sufferers except for the few pretentious mido crass are taking your arrival as another opportunity for ostentatious shopping. Wako na pesa and you should see how they nonchalantly eye each&amp;rsquo;s others tray as if to see who wins with the most full shopping.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that?&amp;hellip;..No, no no no, am not calling anyone an idiot here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We jua tu &amp;hellip; we the poor know plain soap and water is as good as any antibacterial soap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that we will stop shaking hands on your account, a greeting is not complete in Afrika if I do not leave the smell of omena I had for lunch on the palms of your hand. How else will you know I&amp;rsquo;ve eated meat? But we promise to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not like we want to ignore you dear corona, but how will we keep indoors yet we get paid per day? If we don&amp;rsquo;t go to mjengo, trust me there will be no ugali at the end of the day. We will not stay indoors kukufa njaa just because you&amp;rsquo;re here to rule the outdoors. It&amp;rsquo;s our outdoors, only politicians and police can keep us indoors after an election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bro, huku sio UK ama U.S. Our savings culture got lost before our ancestors died, they never managed to find it and we have no social welfare other than shillingi 2,000 per month if you are over 70. Yes, per month. We try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know you think you will collapse our economy, LOL! Shock on you, our government has been screwing our uchumi for several years now&amp;hellip;. and we still here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ain&amp;rsquo;t even gonna worry about you killing us, cancer is now friends with Kenya just incase you have been hiding in a cave until now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also get killed by police stray bullets all the time, so dude - no biggie there. Do you even know the road accident statistics in Kenya? If you knew how we die daily of motorcycle and bus accidents, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even bother to stop here. Sawa baba? Umepoteza fare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are more likely to die of a cholera attack than to be killed by you bro. For us, everday is a run escape from death. We are the walking dead. Death is part of our lives, the shadow that lingers over us from the time the umbilical cord is cut and buried behind the house, to the time we fundraise for expensive arrangements to bury a no longer useful block of dead meat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death can be fall us anytime and we are not scared. If it comes, let it come. Why worry over what we can&amp;rsquo;t control? Everything dies, right? Even you corona will die!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We welcome all kinds of visitors to Kenya, hakuna matata, karibu sana. Enjoy our beaches, tourists are leaving to create room for you. Do make a visit to the Mara and by the time you leave our beautiful country all we ask is: please take most of our politicians with you, they love free rides, alot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/permalink.php?story_fbid=2621148771543767&amp;amp;id=100009460091433&#34;&gt;Samuel Mang&amp;rsquo;era&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon I was sitting outside in the sun on the patio. I saw a yellowjacket land on some of the mullein that grows in patches. The yellowjacket was collecting fuzz off the leaves with her mandibles, working it into a ball, and flying away. Back at the nest, she must have been digesting it into pure cellulose and using it to build nest cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went inside and checked my phone. On it was an email from my landlord. Anna lost her job, so we are trying to move out of our expensive apartment a month early. The message said &amp;ldquo;In order for you to move out a month early, you will need to advertise and show your apartment. Once you have found a replacement, we will need to approve them and have them sign a new lease.&amp;rdquo; No mention of job loss, global pandemic, or the Governer&amp;rsquo;s order to stay at home. About a month ago, this may not have bothered me. But as time goes on, and there are more reports of people of Anna &amp;amp; I&amp;rsquo;s age being hospitalized due to the virus, I realized that showing our apartment to strangers from Craigslist was not an option at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By May the virus may have slowed its spread. But outside my little courtyard, on Agua Fria, I still hear just about the same amount of traffic every day. I hear that just a week ago there were tourists from nationwide all over the plaza, and most businesses were open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the range of responses in Kenya are likely the same as they are worldwide. No one can predict how bad it will be. Some choose to make fun. Some choose to isolate themselves. Some choose to ignore it. I guess this is what I choose—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be present for what I have&lt;br&gt;
To not worry about what&amp;rsquo;s later&lt;br&gt;
To take care of myself as much as I can&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this isolation journal started off with the wrong title. Physically, we are all isolated. But in experience, I think we are together. We are all a part&amp;hellip; of something larger.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - Dishes</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night I washed the dishes left over from lunch. I washed them quickly at first, since washing dishes is such a boring task that has to be done every day. Long ago, it seems, I had determined that a chore like washing dishes held no real value, except in the clean dishes maybe—but in the act, the act of washing dishes there was nothing valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wash the dishes I turned on the water until it was warm. But while the water was flowing I placed some of the dishes, including a bowl and cutting board, in the sink so the water would run into them and start the cleaning process. I have a spray bottle  loaded with a mixture of Dr. Bronners &amp;ldquo;All One&amp;rdquo; soap and water, that when shook creates instant suds. This I use to spray the dishes. It makes one bottle of soap last a few months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the water began to warm I did feel that I was in a kind of hurry. I was rushing to get the dishes done. Then I smelled the good scent of the lavender Bronner&amp;rsquo;s soap, and also the warm water on my hands. And I started to wonder why I was in a hurry. All I had to do after this was go to sleep. There was nothing to rush to, unless it was bed, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t usually end up very restful if rushed. Sleep can&amp;rsquo;t be rushed, for example. It takes a set amount of time for the body to recover each night. I realized there wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything to hurry-up towards, so I slowed down washing the dishes and washed each one very carefully. As I write now, I even remember what each dish looked like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the days spread out and slowly warm, birds have appeared on the rear patio. When money wasn&amp;rsquo;t as tight I walked down Agua Fria to buy seed for them, putting it on a worn out stand someone had put up long ago. The plywood platform was cracked and feathered from years of rain, snow, and sun. But the canyon towhees, spotted towhees, sparrows, wrens, and one thrasher enjoyed the seed all the same. Now that we have no seed to offer, the birds eat seeds from weeds that we let grow and die last summer. And they bathe and drink out of a ceramic basin Anna made that I set on an sumac tree stump. I am glad we neglected the patio and let the native weeds grow, because now the birds have food. Yesterday I saw several eating buds from the apple tree. They didn&amp;rsquo;t destroy the whole bud, though. They just took a little bite off each one. And when they drink water, two sips is enough. Yesterday I tried some of an apple bud. It was slightly bitter and sweet and tasted like the finest summer salad you can imagine.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinnickinnic</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/kinnickinnic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 12:07:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/kinnickinnic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kinnickinnic&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me tell you&lt;br&gt;
a story —&lt;br&gt;
It was&lt;br&gt;
spring&lt;br&gt;
They&lt;br&gt;
two of Them&lt;br&gt;
Moved through the mountains&lt;br&gt;
as the snow left behind&lt;br&gt;
wet rocks, trickles of&lt;br&gt;
water&lt;br&gt;
and cold mud—&lt;br&gt;
Moved through the mountains, from low&lt;br&gt;
to high, two of them&lt;br&gt;
through the cold mud&lt;br&gt;
and over drying rocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had with them&lt;br&gt;
red willow stems&lt;br&gt;
from lower down&lt;br&gt;
and larch boughs that they cut to sleep on.&lt;br&gt;
They stayed in them&lt;br&gt;
—the mountains&lt;br&gt;
to summer when&lt;br&gt;
the deer came higher for cool grass&lt;br&gt;
and marmots whistled across valleys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it was&lt;br&gt;
that rain came more often&lt;br&gt;
it rained a lot, and the slopes became&lt;br&gt;
flowers.&lt;br&gt;
It was so quiet there, they knew&lt;br&gt;
that it was quiet&lt;br&gt;
because they had heard noise elsewhere&lt;br&gt;
—and they knew that this here,&lt;br&gt;
this was quiet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staying at lakes, they went looking&lt;br&gt;
for wild kinnickinnic, loved by bears&lt;br&gt;
its thick, glossy leaves&lt;br&gt;
and soft red berries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They took&lt;br&gt;
what time they had.&lt;br&gt;
They laid down&lt;br&gt;
as fall came&lt;br&gt;
and snow collected on them.&lt;br&gt;
And some say they became boulders,&lt;br&gt;
or always were.&lt;br&gt;
And some say they became trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;~~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, some of which I understand, and some I don&amp;rsquo;t, I have experienced several episodes of ambiguous loss over the last several years. As psychology and relationships have been put under the microscope of science, terms like ambiguous loss have been invented. The term means the ending of a relationship or life circumstance that remain unresolved. Due to the unresolved aspect, our minds, the constant inventors, try and come to some conclusion about the situation—despite a lack of facts or communication. This often leads to vicious cycles of self-blame, blaming others, or depression. Ambiguous loss can happen through the death of someone that doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, the end of a friendship where agreements (to be civil, to treat one another as human, to attempt to see both sides) were broken and the hurt was never resolved&amp;hellip; and in other ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though fancy terms like this often cause me to cast a weather eye in their direction, this one actually does put a phrase to something that I think many people experience, yet don&amp;rsquo;t know how to understand or resolve. The painful point of ambiguous loss is the unresolvable aspect. How does a person move forward with something that is unresolvable? For some reason, the only thing that has helped me is embracing a simple fact: you are not alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person tends to need other people. The fact of knowing that someone else, not even someone necessarily present, cares and thinks about them, or is even experiencing what they are experiencing, matters. When people or relationships are lacking, it is maybe a default to look at oneself and try to determine what&amp;rsquo;s wrong within, or what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with the world. I&amp;rsquo;m guilty of both these things, maybe everyone is from time to time. So when year after year, friendship after friendship, ends in ambiguous loss (is it distance? did I say something? are people busy? do they care? am I likeable? why is society so stressful? what really matters?) it tends to drive a person into the ground. To be honest, I was often thinking about suicide this summer, because I was driven into the ground after many such events. Add to the fact that it seems impossible for my writing to be published, I came to the conclusion that I was adding no value to the world—in fact since everyone seemed to abandoning me, maybe all I was adding was pain—and thus the old story of &amp;ldquo;they would all be better off without me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this story is false, and suicide is always a mistake. Yet from deep in the pit of despair it&amp;rsquo;s hard to understand that. (I&amp;rsquo;m OK now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I was talking to Anna, feeling down that even in the midst of a time when I hear many people are coming together, mending hurts, focusing on kindness, I had yet to receive any notes or comments of care from friends. While this is selfish (why aren&amp;rsquo;t people talking to me?) it has to be something a lot of people are feeling. And I realized last night that maybe the fact of the matter is, with all these never-to-be-resolved situations that pounded me into the ground like a railroad spike—that these same people, with whom I have the disagreements, are just as afraid about trying to resolve them as I am. And even though these situations may never be resolved, I found comfort in that fact, and like a bread-crumb trail into another place it led me on to a hopefully different understanding, of resolution without resolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-wish-for-people-a-perspective-shift&#34;&gt;I wish for people a perspective shift&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Current times are unique, because they hard for almost everyone right now. I, as a constant and probably neurotic observer, have felt witness to degradation of social contracts and real care through the overabundance of exhaustive communication. I wish for people a perspective shift. Right now, it&amp;rsquo;s probably easy as hell to be completely entombed in technology. But the dopamine cycle that rages inside of us through the spinning feeds of images tends to leave us exhausted and unsatisfied, with a dull ache behind the eyes and an empty space inside that cannot be filled by those immaterial and forgettable experiences. I wish for people to seek out something more real. I wish for them to set aside the unimportant and to seek silence from which constant stimulation protects us. Not to claim I know a prescription, but to express that honesty, forgiveness, connection, understanding, and the effort that drives such things maybe harder yet more important than cutting the old habit rut deeper. Write letters, go on walks, bake bread, call old friends, stare at the sky, watch the greening ground, listen to the rain, watch snow melt, listen to the wind, call your grandparents, turn your internet off, learn to cook better, think of others, more importantly &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; for others. If you have someone in your life you can call a friend, you are wealthy. If you have a relationship that could be mended, attempt to mend it. These are all obvious things, that, for some reason, have ended up in the broom closet of our lives. I think they are worth more than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love you all,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Hudson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Body of Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-body-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 07:15:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-body-of-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About ten years ago I carried a camera with me wherever I went. It was mostly film rangefinders back then—Leicas, Bronicas, Olympus XAs, a Zeiss or two—and I had the film developed. And I scanned it myself. I posted the photos to Flickr. I had thousands of photos there. I switched to DSLRS after a while, then back and forth, then went digital for good when film developing started to get ever more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About five years ago I deleted that Flickr account and posted on Instagram. Then about six months ago I deleted the Instagram account. And so lately the thousands of photos have existed only on my backup drives, nowhere that anyone could access them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kept to myself, I have wondered what the point of all those years of photo taking was. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help myself, the world was so beautiful that I had to take photos. I think, if not stifled, every person feels this way about life on earth at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2013 I left Nebraska and headed for places I&amp;rsquo;d never been. I took a few photos during the next four years, but mostly I observed and thought. The mystery of life, and what it was all about, what mattered to me, and to others—where I was going, and what I should do—all these things I worked out over and over again in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work, the writing and photos, has since coalesced into a coherent vision of a life that I lived—something like a dream, a thread, or a stream—that keeps unspooling and going around in different ways. After battling with the idea of publishing, agents, and all that garbage, I decided to put the entire project on the internet for free, at the rate of 1 to 3 posts per week, for everyone to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can follow along here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://write.as/bodyofwater&#34;&gt;A Body of Water&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Hudson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardner Farm</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/gardner-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 15:35:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/gardner-farm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/HLG_4472.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Great Uncle Bob fishing in the Brooks Range&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/HLG_4474.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gun on fir my dad planted fifty years ago&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/HLG_4483.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Dad showing size of fir fifty years ago&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/HLG_4500.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Oregon Coast&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/HLG_4507.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Smugglers Cove&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/HLG_4508.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Astoria&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 10:56:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/holidays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/20191125-HLG_4190.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/20191125-HLG_4193.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/20191125-HLG_4194.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/20191125-HLG_4197.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/20191125-HLG_4199.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;centerphotos-by-annacenter&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Photos by Anna&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year I make a playlist of holiday music. It has a winter theme, I guess mostly drawn from the feeling of the season. Here are this year and the last two years worth—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5HgxzyRioJ8CAXZnM83bfv?si=2DvHC-UcQO2I3MD2koSHWw&#34;&gt;🎄Holidays, Vol. 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/1ysa2bATHjbUQLAsoIZuPr?si=Mz4N34fNRY-Y5bpIM39JpQ&#34;&gt;❄️Holidays, Vol. 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/3xzirZ8VT0I6YyL9AxGo7m?si=RQanxCHEQ1WerWpQOe3mGQ&#34;&gt;⛄️Holidays, Vol. 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 06:25:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It is difficult to get the news from poems&lt;br&gt;
yet men die miserably every day&lt;br&gt;
for lack of what is found there.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— William Carlos Williams&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I remember wandering in the woods in Maine, not long ago, and I saw a tree stump. And I thought, how worthless this stump. The tree has died, and there is nothing left but a jagged place, taking up space. And yet, as we know now, trees, for some reason, keep other trees &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Hidden-Life-Trees-Communicate_Discoveries-Secret/dp/1771642483&#34;&gt;alive long after death&lt;/a&gt;. No one knows why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a thought at that moment: poetry is the most worthless thing, the most useless thing. It has no purpose, it makes little money, and yet, as WCW said above, people die every day knowing everything but poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It made sense, in that moment, that I had come to write poetry, and this book &amp;ldquo;A Body of Water&amp;rdquo;. You see, like most people, I thought poetry was either slam or long old ballads, or Leaves of Grass for the longest time. It turns out: poetry is simply distilled language. It is crystalized examples of our main way of communicating: words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poetry can be a story. It can be a description. It can be three words. It can be a single thought, one sentence. It can be a whole book with a narrative. It lends itself to many things. It&amp;rsquo;s not all emotional. It can be scientific. It is flexible as the language it is born from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to write about this because I think poetry matters. And I want people to know that it&amp;rsquo;s more than &amp;ldquo;going light and knowing flowers,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;what you will do with this one precious life.&amp;rdquo; Poetry is maybe not something with wide appeal, but it should be, especially today. The problem with poetry is that it takes presence, awareness, pause, and reflection to absorb. And these things are in short supply these days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is so much &amp;ldquo;news&amp;rdquo; now, it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to get away from it. Endless feeds of every kind, enouraging a kind of incessant need to consume. Continuous consumption becomes a habit, and there are hooks thrown into you by the platforms that demand it, such as friends and connections, and then the platforms profit from our attention. I am not using any platforms or news apps anymore, for months now, and the shift has been enourmous. I have felt incredibly isolated, because no one really writes letters or emails or text messages anymore. The platforms have gobbled up all connection and demanded that people use them instead of the Old Ways. That&amp;rsquo;s ok, because it has given me more time to think, and to be alone, which I actually enjoy. Though it is hard to feel valued, as I wrote in Sharing a month or so ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I return to thinking of that old stump (and how &amp;ldquo;the aged pine grows old alone in it&amp;rsquo;s canyon&amp;rdquo;). And I don&amp;rsquo;t despair. I think of how everything needs everything, and by being and writing, I too am doing that work. The work of the old stump in the woods, the old pine in the canyon, the old words that one person my come across once a century, that change everything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting A Podcast</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/starting-a-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 20:13:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/starting-a-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have thought about starting a podcast for years. But the ideas never congealed. Just recently, though, I came to an idea that has some momentum. Over the last year I wrote a book called A Body of Water. The podcast will be about publishing this book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book itself is a loosely connected narrative of poems about my search for home over about four years time. It also has themes of impermanence, interbeing, and ecology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The podcast, I hope, will bring this book to more people than it sees sitting on my hard drive. It&amp;rsquo;s also important that the book is read aloud, because a person reading something to someone else is a more complete experience than someone reading in silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brief sidenote: books used to be read aloud for entertainment. In fact, reading silently to oneself used to be considered odd. And then, of course, there are the old stories, the culture, skills, and knowledge that have been passed down through spoken words since before time was counted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.8.21-Starting-A-Podcast-1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know how long I will make the podcast. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that telling the story of the book, the story of the story, will lend more clarity about a way forward. If anything, it will be good place to practice reading, writing, and speaking in a new way. And also to share some of the great music I listen to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-listen-herepodcastcenter&#34;&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/podcast&#34;&gt;Listen Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Share</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/why-i-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 19:40:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/why-i-share/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After deleting my Instagram account, I have been thinking a lot about sharing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was growing up, sharing was partly learned. It felt hard at first. It usually meant giving  away something that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get back. It meant a comittment of a resource to some person or purpose. Like a juicebox at lunch, or a seat at a table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, once a person learns to share, it feels good. At its root sharing is an inclusive act. Inclusivity feels better than exclusivity. Generosity has been proven to produce good feelings in giver and receiver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with this, there is an unlearned human need to share. Sharing begets connection, which creates and maintains relationships. And you can see the innate generosity of humans in how children always want to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The earth is the original sharer, or gift. Being born on earth, we are completely dependent on her. Just how a grizzly is dependent on salmon runs, so we are dependent on rainfall, snowmelt, soil, weather, trees… As society has expanded, and technology has grown, we are actually more dependent on the earth than before—though at first it seems opposite. The ways we are dependent on it have simply been confused and hidden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ability to share comes from having something. I find it interesting I often see those with the most reluctant to share, whether it&amp;rsquo;s friends, resources, space. And those with the least the most willing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think about the original gift of life, of just having a life, and it inspires, in me, a feeling of wanting to give back. I think this is where the deepest parts of my motivation to keep writing, keep working come from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading, and check out this podcast episode about &lt;a href=&#34;https://charleseisenstein.org/podcasts/new-and-ancient-story-podcast/lynne-twist-a-conversation-about-living-in-the-gift-e37/&#34;&gt;sharing and gifts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Ponderosa</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/three-ponderosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 22:38:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/three-ponderosa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Close the eyes, and slip in&lt;br&gt;
to that dark space.&lt;br&gt;
A moment, then none.&lt;br&gt;
No time.&lt;br&gt;
I cannot explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deep&lt;br&gt;
in the pine woods&lt;br&gt;
the water running by logs&lt;br&gt;
and rafts&lt;br&gt;
of flowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I come back, then go again.&lt;br&gt;
A breath, or maybe more time passes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the dark: wavy changy patterns, like the bark&lt;br&gt;
of Ponderosa.&lt;br&gt;
The old trees dance so slow.&lt;br&gt;
And the moons soft glow.&lt;br&gt;
I can&amp;rsquo;t even &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt;, anymore:&lt;br&gt;
who I am&lt;br&gt;
or how I&amp;rsquo;ll be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Way</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 22:33:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Times</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/hard-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 07:35:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/hard-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Things have been rough lately, or longly, for about two years now. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I wrote much about it, keeping difficulty to myself here and there, not wanting to bring anyone down, but now that I can see some kind of end, or at least some kind of change, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a few things down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, over the last four or so years Anna and I have been mostly living in remote places, far away from friends, community, and support. We were living in such a way to come close to what interested us, and also because we didn&amp;rsquo;t know the answers to the questions we were asking: where is home? How to live? What really matters? Through trying life of different kinds in places ranging from Washington to Maine, we arrived at some of these answers. We also encountered hardship, loneliness (a rather new feeling for Anna, who grew up surrounded by family and friends), abuse, and rejection. Everyone wants there to be a good side, a light side to the difficulty people encounter, and there usually is. But something I think that people maybe don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear is sometimes there isn&amp;rsquo;t a bright side. Sometimes there is no silver lining. Sometimes things just suck for a long, long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When things suck for a very long time, one begins to question themselves. Is it me? Is it the choices I&amp;rsquo;ve made, that have driven me to loneliness and despair? And of course the answer is in part: yes. It is you. Especially if you&amp;rsquo;ve had the wherewithal to make choices (some people don&amp;rsquo;t have such a thing as choice). This realization of responsibility for one&amp;rsquo;s choices is maybe one of the most difficult truths I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered in life. The reality is: we don&amp;rsquo;t know where our choices will lead us, or what the questions will cause to work within us. What seemed like an honest thought or need can be endlessly elusive. And I find the closer to the grain that I cut the more the point of my action eludes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What things sucking for a long time does, however, is create a kind of tarnished wisdom about life. If you want, though I&amp;rsquo;d rather not refer to it this way, you could say that this is the &amp;ldquo;silver lining.&amp;rdquo; But the reality is that it&amp;rsquo;s only a positive in retrospect, and the marks of hardness and difficulty maybe never leave a person. That&amp;rsquo;s why the lesson sticks, and that&amp;rsquo;s where the wisdom comes from. When the pain is driven so deep it can never be forgotten. The old adage: one thorn of experience is worth a whole wilderness of warning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, Anna and I moved to Santa Fe, figuring it would be an easy move, just an hour and a half south, a few friends, lots of jobs. Instead it took about two months (of searching beforehand and while staying at a friends) to find a place that then was more expensive than any place either of us had ever paid for. Anna interviewed for a month before finding a job, feeling worthless, judged, and ignored in the process. The friends we had, apart from one, have been so far hard to understand and not very inviting or supportive. This would have been alright if not for it coming on the tail of three or so years of hardship and loneliness. Being on the back of that, and also receiving rejection after rejection from many publications in my attempt to publish writing and photos (and also this book I&amp;rsquo;ve written), this final push in a place we hoped would be welcoming has been an &amp;ldquo;out of the frying pan and into the fire&amp;rdquo; kind of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think in many cases what people are driven to do in this situation is to try and get rid of the difficult part of life immediately, by whatever means possible. However, I still think experiences like this are valuable, and they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be discarded as though worthless. I think that experiences of our essential loneliness are profoundly important. But they are very hard to bear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat outside a few nights ago, feeling more depressed than I have in a very long time.  I started crying and by some strange circumstance it also started raining. Little events like these happen to me often. I often feel like the world outside of human constructs is my true home, and that in a strange way it listens and holds me no matter what happens. It will always be there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it really does feel like the entire human world is conspiring against you. The core of my feeling on the patio was a complete lack of being valued. Things have been rough at work lately, and also with certain very important interpersonal relationships. Feeling a lack of value, like a piece of trash to be discarded by the rest of society, is basically the lowest a person can go. To feel unwelcome, unwanted, and uncared for brings about the deepest depression a person can experience. I think this is how people who are far less fortunate than me, such as the houseless and the incarcerated, feel on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, I have things that I love. I love to walk. I love music. I love to cook. I still  love taking beautiful photos. I love Anna. I love my family, and Anna&amp;rsquo;s family. I love the friends I have in distant places. I love technology. I love Thom Yorke. I love the taste of the bread Anna is getting better at baking. I love this tea I discovered called cota, that grows in groves along the Santa Fe river near where I live. I love my sister. I love my brothers. I love rain after sun and sun after rain. I love the pine-scent. I love the lizards that gulp down ants and live in the bushes on the patio. I love learning and reading. There is so much I love. And in this, I find value. And the value is reflected back at me: what I love, loves me, even if it is a rock, river, or tree. The world itself loves me back. And feeling that love, I will never be alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Progress</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/no-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 06:55:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/no-progress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For many, this is where the story of their life begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In such a room, when they had few things, life was charted to become larger, to include more. Maybe, though, there was a part of Steve Jobs that wished he had never left that room.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, this is where life begins, but also where it ends. I have thought carefully about what I want, and tried things. There is something so beautiful in this empty room to me. The beauty is a kind of space. There is space there. Space, like time, is interesting in that as I grow older I see that both space and time become rare commodities. Space to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may seem like a counter-culture statement. But I would like to say this idea of space and simplicity is a place lived in on it&amp;rsquo;s own. It is not against anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never wanting more than that room is like choosing a fork in a trail&lt;br&gt;
that is narrower and also wider&lt;br&gt;
that has brought me somewhere&lt;br&gt;
both very old yet always new.&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s less clear, this Way,&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s very quiet though.&lt;br&gt;
And it has taught me to not have fear.&lt;br&gt;
There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of space here,&lt;br&gt;
to garden in, to cook, to sleep and eat,&lt;br&gt;
to make mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So much of my work is about a single idea: losing sight of myself. Learning, re-learning to not think, and not do. Yet life we are told should be about building up a self—making it larger and larger, happier and happier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to rest in a darkened room&lt;br&gt;
with a place to sit, music, and a cup of tea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.6.16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;19.6.16&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa Fe</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/santa-fe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 08:37:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/santa-fe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/1-Anna-June.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Anna Koenig Artist&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/2-Anna-June.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Anna Koenig Artist&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the corner of Cerillos and Don Diego I saw a man working on his car as I crossed the street. He had the hood up and was talking with a friend. &amp;ldquo;Is that a carbeurator?&amp;rdquo; I asked as I walked up. &amp;ldquo;Oh yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s a carbeurator. Got the original clutch in it too man, like a hundred fifty thousand on it.&amp;rdquo; We talked about how much easier it was to work on carbuerated cars rather than fuel injection. It turned out he and his friend were changing the fluids and getting the car ready for a move. &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;ve been living in this place 12 years man, and they just raised the rent $400. Just like that,&amp;rdquo; he snapped his fingers. &amp;ldquo;And so I&amp;rsquo;m moving south.&amp;rdquo; I told him I was looking for a place too, but from Taos for about a month and a half. My lease had just ended the day before, so I was staying at a friends with all me and my girlfriends stuff in the back of our pickup. He gave me some tips and said to check a few places. He said to look on Craigslist for sublets or house sitting. &amp;ldquo;I made it into a job but I never found nothing here man. I&amp;rsquo;m going to live in this thing,&amp;rdquo; he pointed at a van parked next to us, with sheets over the windows &amp;ldquo;until that place down south opens up. I&amp;rsquo;m camping early man!&amp;rdquo; he said laughing. We talked for a while longer. I learned he grew up in Española, where he said me and my girlfriend &amp;ldquo;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t really fit.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;But you know man I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fit where you come from, no offense.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;No but you could hang out with us,&amp;rdquo; I said. He and his friend laughed.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Well good luck, I&amp;rsquo;ll pray for you,&amp;rdquo; he said, clasping his hands at his chest.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;You too man, good luck.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;If you need a place to stay, let me know,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re with a friend, but thanks.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Well if you need something just come back here. Let me know. Let me know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Alright,&amp;rdquo; I said shaking his hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walked away feeling awkward and humbled: someone I barely knew, maybe in worse position than me, yet offering what he could. As we waited to cross Don Diego Mercedes and BMWs ripped by.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked down the street, and into our friend&amp;rsquo;s house, and opened our laptops to look at Craigstlist again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasoned Wood</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/seasoned-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 14:57:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/seasoned-wood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seasoned Wood&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A River Flows To The Sea</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-river-flows-to-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 08:52:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-river-flows-to-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s something funny—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So many times I&amp;rsquo;ve been told I can&amp;rsquo;t do what I want to do, by so many people, in so many ways. It happens almost every day. And then you might think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;well, I guess this guy is just really selfish, self-centered, and ignorant.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s not true either though, because I do listen: to how plants grow, to how animals live, to how people care and support one another. But I don&amp;rsquo;t let myself listen to things that don&amp;rsquo;t make sense to me. And it isn&amp;rsquo;t an ego-based rejection, it&amp;rsquo;s a thought of what will make me most free. Free from fear, free from anger, free from control. Oh no, it&amp;rsquo;s not easy and blissful at all. In fact, doing what I do is the opposite of easy and blissful. No, it&amp;rsquo;s the hard work. The work that benefits no one else but myself, for now. But I believe in the idea of honing oneself through work like this, whether it&amp;rsquo;s with others, or alone. And through that honing becoming more fully human, and able to know the answers, and be there for others whether it&amp;rsquo;s a landscape, a plant, a community, or another person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a river wandered into the desert in many little streams it would dry up and disappear. But if it keeps its main course it will flow to the ocean. Poetic, maybe, but in my route through life I&amp;rsquo;ve found it to be true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep telling me I&amp;rsquo;m wrong, that I&amp;rsquo;m taking the wrong course, that I&amp;rsquo;ll never amount to anything. I don&amp;rsquo;t care about proving you wrong, because I know it&amp;rsquo;s not me you&amp;rsquo;re talking to. You&amp;rsquo;re speaking to your own fears, of what you think is possible or impossible. I&amp;rsquo;ll prove one thing: that a human being can remain free and alive through a life, like a river flowing cleanly down through so many things and down to the sea.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodies - A Poem</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/bodies-a-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 10:56:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/bodies-a-poem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo: Anna off trail in the Jemez&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My body, yours&lt;br&gt;
the forest floor&lt;br&gt;
body of earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High mountains&lt;br&gt;
body of stone&lt;br&gt;
left alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rock cañon&lt;br&gt;
and a sheep skull, full curl&lt;br&gt;
that nobody claimed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calcium, schist to granite from magma&lt;br&gt;
old cottonwood, sand&lt;br&gt;
thirteen tracks of a roadrunner&lt;br&gt;
disappearing into the &lt;em&gt;body of a desert.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Sagebrush. Chimayo. Chamisa. Conejos&lt;br&gt;
river running&lt;br&gt;
under a bridge.&lt;br&gt;
Bosqué, cottonwoods, los alamos&lt;br&gt;
huge valley, snow body&lt;br&gt;
wide open, hot, steam from spring body—&lt;br&gt;
but cold that same night on our bodies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walking again, up the same way&lt;br&gt;
but without a trail&lt;br&gt;
to where we hid our bikes.&lt;br&gt;
Riding in, then out&lt;br&gt;
along a body&lt;br&gt;
and in a body—&lt;br&gt;
Being somebody?&lt;br&gt;
Being nobody.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Handbook For Ethical Instagram Use</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-handbook-for-ethical-instagram-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 09:18:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-handbook-for-ethical-instagram-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I started writing this out as a short post for Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to put it there &amp;amp; here, because I wanted to write a little more about each point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideas-for-ethical-instagram-use&#34;&gt;Ideas For Ethical Instagram Use&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-consider-why-you-are-posting-before-you-post&#34;&gt;1. Consider why you are posting before you post&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-do-not-attempt-to-make-your-life-look-enviable-or-better-than-it-is&#34;&gt;2. Do not attempt to make your life look enviable, or better than it is&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For some reason, this is almost the reason Instagram exists. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a harmful practice, and creates competition and instead of collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-do-not-use-geotags-also-consider-why-you-want-to-geotag&#34;&gt;3. Do not use geotags (also, consider why you want to geotag)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People argue there are ethical ways to geotag. I disagree. There are too many people using Instagram, and the algorithms are too successful  at funneling likes and views to already overpopular things. Just leave them off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-think-collaborative-not-competitive&#34;&gt;4. Think: collaborative, not competitive!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-treat-people-as-people-not-potential-audience-or-customers&#34;&gt;5. Treat people as people, not potential audience or customers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is truly the age of the Artist Entrepreneur. We have become our own platforms. We must do everything from conceptualizing, to marketing, to shipping. This can drive people to treat others as potential audience rather than just human beings. It turns each of us into agents—for ourselves. While this approach might be effective, I believe it undermines our common humanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-do-not-align-your-self-worth-with-how-much-people-like-you-in-other-words-work-on-self-compassion-not-self-esteem&#34;&gt;6. Do not align your self-worth with how much people like you. In other words, work on self-compassion, not self-esteem.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &amp;ldquo;Fearless Heart&amp;rdquo; Thupten Jingpa, the translator for the Dalai Lama, argues that self-esteem and self-compassion are two different things. Self-esteem is fragile because it is often attached to success, or external circumstances. Self-compassion is self love. And love means acceptance. Self-esteem has something to prove. Self-love is simply an embracing of all things, ideal, or unideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-fullycompletelydeeply-consider-your-impact&#34;&gt;7. Fully/completely/deeply consider your impact&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instagram affects the real world, even though we don&amp;rsquo;t see it directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-limit-use-to-a-healthy-level&#34;&gt;8. Limit use to a healthy level&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are timers, usually called Digital Wellbeing, available on most smartphones now. Use them!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:12:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/slow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A long time ago I wrote every day for a year. That blog was called Slow Gospel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow Gospel offered a space where people could slow down, even for a moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entries were brief, not longer than 500 words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was back in 2012. Things were already humming along pretty quickly back then in the big old world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a year I took the site down. It did not gain an audience as I hoped it would. So it lost meaning for me to write it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At one point, I wanted to write longer things. I had an idea that writing longer meant I would eventually write a book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought longer writing meant the writing was more sophisticated and meant more, even though I knew simplicity was actually complex, and multilayered, hitched to everything if done right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to turn aside from that route, and begin writing even shorter than before. Distilling experiences, thoughts, feelings down to a few lines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now I feel the urge to write shorter and shorter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to think about people, not about problems. What are people attracted to? What gives a sense of relief?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pounding down on the problems of the world creates more problems. It&amp;rsquo;s like weeding. Remove a plant, and there is space for another. The weeds will never end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll cook them for my meal.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hardest Work</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-hardest-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 19:12:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-hardest-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Photo above by Demetria Provatas, me above the Hudson River in New York&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I feel my work over the last year, and maybe longer, has been dark. It&amp;rsquo;s  been some dark times lately, for many people. And my own individual suffering was increased by a series of mistakes I made that resulted in an abusive situation I had a difficult time extracting myself from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not asking anyone to listen to the difficulties, as I have had several willing and loving friends and family members to listen. It&amp;rsquo;s strange though, how after leaving a traumatic situation, it still can haunt your waking and dreaming for months and even years. I guess for some it can take the form of a permanent illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to turn a corner, though. I have lately been thinking about what I am &lt;strong&gt;For&lt;/strong&gt; rather than &lt;strong&gt;Against&lt;/strong&gt;. And in the midst of difficulties, as the result of mistakes, a person can learn a lot. I have often wondered why the route I chose over the last span of lifetime has been so hard on myself: isolating, threadbare, tumultuous, uncertain: you name it, I&amp;rsquo;ve probably been through it. I have a theory that it has been a kind of Jedi training, to strip away all that is unnecessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I look in the mirror, I see a changed person. Nowadays, a rather dried out, tanned one, from the New Mexico climate. But there is rigidity in my face and a quiet depth in my eyes that may not have been so clear before. There is also light and warmth. I think the laying-on of sufferings of late has indeed changed me. But the goodness and light I have been given will win out in the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, I&amp;rsquo;m not a victim. I made all the choices I made, with awareness there would be a a certain result, and that is a privilege. Some have no choices at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I still have choice and will, and strength, energy, and light left in me, I, by code of my own ethics, must use it for good. I have such a hard time trying to understand that though. It is so hard to &amp;ldquo;help.&amp;rdquo; It is so hard to know how to say things to people that are both understanding yet challenging. And in the end, should I be the one challenging, understanding, doing good, &amp;ldquo;helping?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I could summarize it all and what I want to do about it, it would be in this book, this beast, this long line of words I&amp;rsquo;m trying to publish: A Body of Water. I think it&amp;rsquo;s my best work yet, and is the closest I&amp;rsquo;ve come to &amp;ldquo;helping&amp;rdquo; anything. I really believe in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always come back to something my mom says, again and again: &amp;ldquo;The hardest work is the work we do on ourselves.&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s true, because &lt;em&gt;our self&lt;/em&gt; shapes the world. Not just through actions, but through view. Our Self is what looks out on Earth, has all these thoughts, divines right from wrong, in our own conduct and others. So I am happy to say, that the work I have done has been the hardest work. The work on myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All for now,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— hudson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass Roundup No. 1</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/grass-roundup-no.-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 14:20:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/grass-roundup-no.-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy April everyone, it&amp;rsquo;s the season of impatience and unpredictable weather. This is the first Grass Roundup of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve written or consumed this month. Read on for the fresh grass scent of new days and things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;watching&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Watching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, &lt;a href=&#34;http://criterionchannel.com&#34;&gt;a new channel&lt;/a&gt; by the Criterion Collection. If you&amp;rsquo;re not already an obscure film junky, you could easily become one. Before now, Criterion Collection films were only available on clunky, archaic DVD discs. Now you can watch almost the whole collection on your phone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-film-picks&#34;&gt;My Film Picks&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.criterionchannel.com/sanjuro&#34;&gt;Sanjuro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A threadbare old ronin helps young warriors in need. Action/Drama.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.criterionchannel.com/videos/cleo-from-5-to-7&#34;&gt;Cléo from 5 to 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Portrait of a famous singer in Paris as she awaits the results of a biopsy. Slice of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.criterionchannel.com/il-sorpasso&#34;&gt;Il Sorpasso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A young student of law takes an unexpected road trip from Rome to Tuscany. Comedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;listening&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been throwing together a &lt;a href=&#34;https://open.spotify.com/user/hudsongardner/playlist/0OLoaXxQ4medCXeDu7s1Ze?si=rd1qBi4-S_mYIPxSOz2hVg&#34;&gt;🌴🏝&lt;/a&gt; playlist. Not done yet but maybe fun to watch the progress. (Click the trees)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote a poem yesterday, and an essay today. Here&amp;rsquo;s the poem—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Song of the canyon wren&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;drips, then slides down a rock.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Smooth, like passing water.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A little voice, amidst voices.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The center of this moment, and everywhere.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Holding it all together.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grass-index&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grass Index&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Grass Journal there are a lot of new things, if you haven&amp;rsquo;t looked lately —&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most popular post so far, may also be the &lt;a href=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/instagram&#34;&gt;most maligned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An article summary, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void&#34;&gt;some of my own thoughts&lt;/a&gt; about addiction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/scones/&#34;&gt;delicious scone recipe&lt;/a&gt; from my girlfriend Anna&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;im-trying-to-publish-a-book&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m Trying To Publish A Book&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am in the process of submitting my manuscript, A Body of Water, to publishers. If you know of a press that publishes full length poetry, written in a narrative format that flows from beginning to end, and has themes of deep ecology and spirituality (but not religion), then let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for this fortnight. Thank you for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Hudson&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Currant Scones Of Life</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/scones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 03:53:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/scones/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These buckwheat-oatmeal scones are surprisingly delicious. Buckwheat lends a cake-like texture and roasty flavor. Additions: toasted nuts, sesame seeds, or whatever you want. Recipe by &lt;a href=&#34;http://annakoenigart.com&#34;&gt;Anna&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dry&#34;&gt;DRY&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 2 cups&lt;/strong&gt; chosen flours (I used ¾ whole wheat, 1/4 buckwheat)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 2 handfuls&lt;/strong&gt; of oats&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1/2 tsp&lt;/strong&gt; salt&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1 tsp&lt;/strong&gt; baking powder &lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘&lt;/strong&gt; Currants to taste (soak awhile in hot water)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1 stick&lt;/strong&gt; cold butter (cut into dry ingredients)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wet&#34;&gt;WET&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;⁘ Large spoonful&lt;/strong&gt; of sourdough starter (dissolve in milk)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1/2 cup&lt;/strong&gt; milk&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1 large&lt;/strong&gt; egg&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘ 1/3 cup&lt;/strong&gt; sugar (or to taste)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;⁘&lt;/strong&gt; zest of a lemon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add wet ingredients to dry&lt;br&gt;
Mix til combined, but don’t overdo  (this helps keep the crumb cake-like—over stirring will toughen the dough)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pat into fat disc and put wrapped in fridge for awhile&lt;br&gt;
Shape desired thickness&lt;br&gt;
Cut into squares / triangles / what have you&lt;br&gt;
Oven at 400+ until bottoms are browned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03-oatmeal-scones-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Dinner (Recipe)</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/late-dinner-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 20:45:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/late-dinner-recipe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Acequia.Snow.9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.03.31-Rice.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rice&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;crackly-toasted-late-dinner-rice-&#34;&gt;Crackly-Toasted Late Dinner Rice 😱&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rice&#34;&gt;Rice&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 cups&lt;/strong&gt; short grain white rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water&lt;/strong&gt;, to cover rice to a depth of 1&amp;rdquo; (or consult your rice cooker instructions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;toppings&#34;&gt;Toppings&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 tbsp&lt;/strong&gt; butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1 tbsp&lt;/strong&gt; good soy sauce (san j, ohsawa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2 cloves&lt;/strong&gt; garlic, smashed &amp;amp; chopped&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; thinly sliced scallions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;method&#34;&gt;Method&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put the rice and water in a pan, cover and bring to a boil. Once it has boiled, lower the heat and simmer for 15 min (or follow rice cooker instructions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The rice should turn out a little dry, and crackly on the bottom. If you want to skip this, just make it normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the rice is cooking, add the butter to a small pan over medium heat and melt. Add the chopped garlic, and cook, stirring, until fragrant. Then add the soy sauce, and stir well, caramelizing it. Turn off once ingredients are well incorporated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check the rice. If it has begun to crackle and smell toasty, it&amp;rsquo;s ready. At this point, its up to you how long you want to cook it. Longer = Drier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serve rice in bowls with sauce spooned over the top. Garnish with scallions. If you&amp;rsquo;re hungry, add a 6 minute egg.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slaying The Instagram Beast</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/instagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/instagram/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last seven years, permit applications for entry into a certain wilderness region in Washington have risen dramatically. In 2011 about 2,800 applications were received. But in 2018 the entries had increased to over 21,500. A similar trend has occurred in other wilderness areas across the USA. Suddenly, the amount of people going to very particular, even remote places, has exploded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are probably many reasons why this has happened—there is a positive trend of people getting outdoors more. However, for certain key zones, it seems more is going on than random chance coupled with an increased interest in going outside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In regards to the popularizing of places both wild and tamed many people have begun to point fingers at social media &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/04/24/vanlife-the-bohemian-social-media-movement&#34;&gt;influencers&lt;/a&gt;. Influencers are essentially trendsetters with massive followings, sometimes hundreds of thousands of people. Over the last six years or so these influencers, particularly those who are #vanlife and outdoors based, began to drop into the &amp;ldquo;most beautiful&amp;rdquo; places, and exploit them for likes and follows—and even money (they are often sponsored)—by shooting nauseatingly beautiful, perfectly posed photos—photos so beautiful, that it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible for a viewer not to imagine themselves right there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cyber-logging&#34;&gt;CYBER LOGGING&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These influencers nowadays would defend themselves to the end, mentioning that they practice leave no trace tagging principles (keep in mind: these principles appeared less than two years ago), and that &amp;ldquo;bringing awareness&amp;rdquo; to places is always positive. People, while on social media, tend to see the world with rose-colored glasses. The only way something can be bad is if you choose to view it as such. Maybe this is because it&amp;rsquo;s very difficult to see your impacts in the physical world when you spend so much time and thought interacting with the digital. Being there, seeing the crowds, seeing the impact of hundreds of people walking on fragile ground, or converging on certain areas of towns, is a lot different than perfectly posed photos, cropped just enough to not show the crowds, or the impact, or the noise of hundreds of other people posing and taking photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In regards to the environment, and capitalism, I see this kind of exploitation of beauty for personal gain by brands and common people as one of the last frontiers of extraction.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s a kind of digital clearcutting. Regarding landscapes, since they have already been dammed, cut, and mined, the final frontier is the exploitation of their beauty for likes and shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About a month ago, I made comments on a variety of Instagram influencer accounts that I felt made posts of this exploitative nature. In particular, they had all recently geotagged the above mentioned wilderness area in Washington. My post was something like &amp;ldquo;Please stop using geotags in places like this for your personal instafame. They are being overrun by too much exposure.&amp;rdquo; I got a variety of responses, most of them negative, with people lashing back at me. Some even took the time to find a single photo of mine from three years ago that I had geotagged. I realized, and already knew, that insults were not a good way to go about educating people. But, I was angry, and had been for a long time. It had finally boiled over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reflecting for an afternoon, I realized I wasn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily angry at those people for not examining their actions. I was angry at what Instagram has done to people, and at people&amp;rsquo;s complicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-beast&#34;&gt;THE BEAST&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Instagram has become a beast. A subtle beast, that dotes and fawns, making me feel better, making me feel like it&amp;rsquo;s necessary—that if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have it, I would be missing out. And I think a lot of people have been entrapped by its honey&amp;rsquo;d barb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last five years, I have often thought about deleting Instagram, but always stopped short. To me, it came down to the idea that without it, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to keep in touch with certain people. Many of my friends post every day, and there is definite value in what they post: everything from their own creative work, to snapshots of their real life, to interesting things they want to share: things and thoughts I&amp;rsquo;d never otherwise see. But after my uncharacteristic and ridiculous burst of anger at random people, I realized that I&amp;rsquo;d had enough. For the time being, I was ready to let go of Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stepping-away&#34;&gt;STEPPING AWAY&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next month, I didn&amp;rsquo;t login to my personal Instagram account a single time. I was surprised: I didn&amp;rsquo;t even miss it. Not checking my phone first thing in the morning allowed me a wealth of free time. It was like a burden had been lifted. The post making, the replying to comments, the reaping of follows and likes: it all ended abruptly. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I had lost anything. Instead, I had gained: time, attention, and sanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the following weeks, I began writing letters to friends, because without Instagram, I no longer knew what they were up to. I read two books, Americanah (Aidiche), and Independent People (Laxness). I learned how to use Github, and coded the website you are reading this on by hand, a major advance in programming skills for me. I suddenly had so much more focus. I felt like a mist had been lifted from my eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;addiction&#34;&gt;ADDICTION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact is, the moment a person touches the Instagram button on their phone, they have initiated a system that harnesses the deepest, most vulnerable part of their brain: the rewards system. You may be familiar with dopamine, the neurotransmitter that is at the core of the system. Everything from the little white heart icons that pop up on a red background, to the way the feed is organized by complex and addictive algorithms, has been engineered to be as seductive as possible: to produce dopamine in people&amp;rsquo;s brains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think seductive is a very important word here, because on the surface Instagram is so real (the content is from our friends) that it&amp;rsquo;s hard to think of it as fake and bad. But in many ways, it is. But it&amp;rsquo;s not bad like cigarettes. Instagram is far more skillful at making you addicted to it. It seduces you by making you think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary, that without it you will be missing out. It leverages our needs for socializing, recognition, and stimulation, and turns them insatiable. Instagram is like water that quenches no thirst.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;compassion&#34;&gt;COMPASSION&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people would say they waste time doing things they don&amp;rsquo;t want to be doing. In this case, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean obligations, but habits. It might be easy to ignore everything I&amp;rsquo;ve said about Instagram so far, because it&amp;rsquo;s easy to think that you are in control of what you&amp;rsquo;re doing. However, anyone who has checked in even precursorily will know that is actually not true. For example, noticing the busy, somewhat uncontrollable nature of mind is one of the first insights of meditation practice. I would submit that Instagram, and maybe phone use in general, is one of those things that&amp;rsquo;s hard to get clear on without close attention to habits. Are you using it, or vise versa?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a hypothesis that companies nowadays, and since advertising was invented, prey on this kind of difficulty of discerning good from bad.&lt;/strong&gt; In an NYTimes article called The Cost of Paying Attention, Matthew Crawford claims that these days we even have to pay for silence. We have to pay not to be advertised to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Silence is now offered as a luxury good. In the business-class lounge at Charles de Gaulle Airport, I heard only the occasional tinkling of a spoon against china. I saw no advertisements on the walls. This silence, more than any other feature, is what makes it feel genuinely luxurious. When you step inside and the automatic doors whoosh shut behind you, the difference is nearly tactile, like slipping out of haircloth into satin. Your brow unfurrows, your neck muscles relax; after 20 minutes you no longer feel exhausted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Outside, in the peon section, is the usual airport cacophony. Because we have allowed our attention to be monetized, if you want yours back you’re going to have to pay for it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another key idea drawn from his writing, and my own experience: Resisting impulses takes effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What if we saw attention in the same way that we saw air or water, as a valuable resource that we hold in common? Perhaps, if we could envision an “attentional commons,” then we could figure out how to protect it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The sad state of this commons is on display everywhere; consider the experience of being in an airport. I have found I have to be careful when going through airport security, because the trays that you place your items in for X-ray screening are now papered with advertisements, and it’s very easy to miss a lipstick-size flash memory stick against a picture of fanned-out L’Oréal lipstick colors.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am already in a state of low-level panic about departure times, possible gate changes and any number of other contingencies. This fresh demand for vigilance, lest I lose the PowerPoint slide show I will be presenting in a few hours, feels like a straightforward conflict between me and L’Oréal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think these compounding factors may be why I personally have had such a hard time focusing, reading books, etc when I was using Instagram daily. Every moment I was doing something &amp;ldquo;less interesting&amp;rdquo; (according to the dopamine-based rewards system) my mind would tell me to pick up my phone: there&amp;rsquo;s something more stimulating there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lacking-something&#34;&gt;LACKING SOMETHING&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These thoughts so far have been drawn from my personal experience of using Instagram as a photographer and writer for about seven years. My experience has most likely been different than yours. For me, Instagram was initially a replacement for Flickr—a place to share my work. But I realized recently that Flickr was not only empurposed with the idea of sharing photos—it was about community and recognition too, at least for me. And online communities have often filled in for real-life communities that I&amp;rsquo;ve lacked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lack of something is a powerful motivator. Feeling a hole, a space that was once filled and is now empty, can compel massive effort. Relationships with other people, for example, are often both the hardest and most rewarding things in our lives. They are hard because we need them for our wellbeing, yet they take effort. They are rewarding because effort deepens them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, Instagram at its core is a panderer of illusory relationships. It makes one feel connected, while actually disconnecting people from the present. It makes one feel involved and accepted, but actually dis-involves, and perpetuates an insatiable need for recognition. Your mileage my vary, however, anecdotally, I have heard a lot of people echoing these same thoughts. But the way friends talk about it is more a vague uneasiness, like they are not really sure what to think of it. Their view of it sways from being terrible to wonderful. In other words, a relationship with Instagram for some can take on the hallmarks of an addiction. Something that is both loathed and loved, with obvious shortcomings, but that for some reason cannot be expelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-it-all-began&#34;&gt;HOW IT ALL BEGAN&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when Instagram first launched, it was innocent enough. There were no sneaky algorithms, stories, geotags, suggested followers, ads (remember that?!), influencers&amp;hellip; etc. It was a simple platform for sharing, used by creative people. The platform itself wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed to be addictive. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t based on fame and capitalism. It was a like a screwdriver. It was a simple tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Facebook acquired the company for $1,000,000,000 on April 9, 2012, everything changed. And now, six-ish years later, all the original founders of Instagram &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2018/11/14/quitting-instagram-shes-one-millions-disillusioned-with-social-media-she-also-helped-create-it/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.5bc33b1c3f3b&#34;&gt;have quit&lt;/a&gt;, and some of the original employees have deleted their accounts. I think that&amp;rsquo;s all I need to say about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-end&#34;&gt;THE END&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have now been off Instagram for almost two months. Apart from my first day off the platform, I haven&amp;rsquo;t received a single message saying that someone has missed my presence there. Coming from posting almost every day, for almost five years, it makes ya think&amp;hellip; how much value was I really adding to people&amp;rsquo;s lives? How much was I receiving? What could I have been doing with that time, and energy? In the time since signing off, as I mentioned before, it seems like I could have been doing a lot. Or, maybe, less. Just enjoying the present moment with a cup of tea, a good book, and occasional glances out the window.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;AFTERWORD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning I woke up and toasted a batch of millet and oats in a small pan I took from my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s house after she died. I added some toasted sesame seeds and some whole milk, along with some raisins and a few grains of salt, sat down, and turned on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://onbeing.org/programs/teju-cole-sitting-together-in-the-dark-feb2019/&#34;&gt;podcast interview&lt;/a&gt; with Teju Cole. Teju, ever since I found out about him, has been a person I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a deep kinship with—someone who is willing to stand on the edge and look at everything, alone. And in the interview, he said just that—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right, but being “woke” is also different from waking up, because it’s a performing — knowing the right things to say so that you don’t get attacked. But the responsibility actually goes deeper than that — like, what does it mean to seek justice?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think about that in relation to [James Baldwin], and it connects to a further thought, which is that in his lifetime he had this early success, and then he lived — he didn’t live long enough, but he lived into some — a bit of old age. He really fell out of favor. He was sort of set up for it: He was black, grew up poor. He was queer, and he was independent-minded. White people attacked him. Black people attacked him. People thought he wasn’t going far enough in his radical ideas. People thought he was going too far. It was incredibly stressful. He couldn’t live here. And it wasn’t only because of racism. It was also because people on the left were attacking him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think what I learned the most from him is not that you can mine his work and find the quote that fits our progressive positions, but what I learned from him is that &lt;strong&gt;taking truly progressive positions can be devastatingly isolating&lt;/strong&gt;. If everyone is woke, you may be called on to be something else, something a bit more difficult than that. If we live in an environment where we take the “right” opinion for granted as a given — “Oh, everybody knows that” — maybe you’re called on to explore the ideas that not everybody knows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Teju Cole&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to share this excerpt because it hit home for me so deeply, I cried. I feel like, for so long, I have been on the edge of things, looking in. The words I wrote above, about Instagram, is just a recent thing I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed of so many. However, I have waited over a month after writing it to publish it, because I know that a lot of people think I&amp;rsquo;m wrong, will take it personally, or think that I am just a fool with an axe to grind. Or maybe, I&amp;rsquo;m the only person who has problems with social media. That&amp;rsquo;s often how it feels. Isolating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last thing I want to say is: I don&amp;rsquo;t think the problems of the world, such as Instagram, can be dismantled by fear-based anger. Fear based anger often motivates a lot of what people do, it&amp;rsquo;s a compelling reason after all: as I mentioned before about the idea of Lacking Something—fear can be the motivator to pre-empt a future lack via action. I have been the victim of fear based anger, particularly with my commenting on Influencers accounts mentioned above. I fear a loss of wild places. But my fear will not drive wise actions. I have to step back and take stock of everything, and then act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess this writing, this thinking, is my best shot at that, for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading ~&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that Teju Cole used to post every day, many times per day, on Instagram. On checking today, his last post was December 26th, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a gap in a leafy hedge&lt;br&gt;
and I watched as a little bird flew in. &lt;br&gt;
Spring rises&lt;br&gt;
like a green mist, up from the ground.&lt;br&gt;
Water is liquid, and comes back from where it was&lt;br&gt;
like spring does.&lt;br&gt;
Always something coming back from something&lt;br&gt;
the beat of a stone, two thumps—&lt;br&gt;
the old heart again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/18.12.27-forest-park.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;18.12.27-forest-park&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/18.12.27-west-hills.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;18.12.27-west-hills&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/18.12.27-rose-garden.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/18.12.27-rhododendron.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/18.12.27-rose-garden-2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filling The Void</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;About twelve years ago, when I was 18, I wound up in college. I remember lots of things from those times, but I often remember hearing how awkward everything was. Maybe it was a buzzword back in those years. I just remember the word being appended to almost every sentence any of my peers uttered. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t that awkward,&amp;rdquo; they would say, about having to talk to a teacher after class. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s so awkward,&amp;rdquo; about a student whose voice cracked when asking a question. Etcetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It struck me as weird that common, everyday scenarios were considered awkward. I figured awkwardness would pass with time. I felt awkward myself. But one place I differed from my peers was that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t into parties that much, and therefore not into drinking. But when I did go to parties, I&amp;rsquo;d sit in a corner and mostly observe what was happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this lonely corner, I came to view alcohol as a social crutch, used to ease all this apparent awkwardness. And for some reason, after that first semester, I decided that I wanted to be OK without crutches—completely OK on my own, without substances to calm me down. No one told me to be that way. And it cost me a lot in terms of social aptitude: most of my friends wanted to go out and get drinks. You may not know this, but, if you&amp;rsquo;re the only person not drinking, the situation is usually not that fun. There&amp;rsquo;s also a pretty high chance you&amp;rsquo;ll be derided by your peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, most of my peers have grown up and don&amp;rsquo;t drink often. I think many of them think about their health, and may not need alcohol to smooth things out these days. But there are others—some who need it still, and some who got habitually trapped, and drink out of habit or addiction. But I still have many questions about those earlier years. Why can some people can drink, yet make it out of the awkward phase without bad habits or addiction? Why do some feel a need to abstain totally (me)? And why do yet others get addicted?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking about the state of society for a long time. I guess it&amp;rsquo;s something I can&amp;rsquo;t stop thinking about. I thought I would have figured it out by now, or given up, but so far neither of those things have happened. However, in regards to some of these questions about addiction and awkwardness , I read an incredible article recently. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;https://thesunmagazine.org/issues/519/filling-the-void&#34;&gt;Filling The Void&lt;/a&gt; by psychologist Bruce K. Alexander. His work offers some alarming insights about the nature of addiction, namely, that it isn&amp;rsquo;t inherent to us as beings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my experiences it&amp;rsquo;s generally accepted that humans are prone to addiction. Addiction is seen as a powerful, dark force we have to resist at all times. But Alexander&amp;rsquo;s research shows that addiction comes from something else, a collection of conditions that political economist Karl Polyani called &lt;strong&gt;dislocation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chevalier&lt;/strong&gt;: So if addiction doesn’t arise from properties of the drug itself, what causes it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander&lt;/strong&gt;: Drug addiction of all kinds arises primarily from the relentlessly increasing dislocation in our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chevalier&lt;/strong&gt;: What do you mean by “dislocation”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander&lt;/strong&gt;: It’s a word political economist Karl Polanyi used to describe alienation or disconnection, a state of being ungrounded and ill at ease. People are dislocated when their vital needs for individual autonomy and belonging are unmet. Dislocated people don’t have a place in the established social order, and they fill that void with addiction. For instance, some young people can’t stop playing video games, because a virtual fantasy world provides the excitement, identity, and meaning that are lacking in their actual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chevalier&lt;/strong&gt;: What causes all this dislocation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexander&lt;/strong&gt;: The social and political system past generations struggled to create has been twisted into a cruel and stupid imperial system dominated by multinational corporations. This is hard for people to admit. Who can bear to face the fact that the consumer society we were raised to cherish is actually making us apathetic, crazy, and vulnerable to addiction? The disconnected, fragmented nature of our culture causes addiction, which causes further fragmentation. Most serious addictions are actually an adaptation to dislocation. To some extent addiction is a functional way of dealing with the problem. Of course, what people really need is to be genuinely recognized and accepted and believed in — to have a purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a follow up to this, I&amp;rsquo;m writing a post about why I quit Instagram. You can read more soon enough. But for now I really recommend you read the article quoted above (link also below), and consider the subtle ways a person can be addicted to things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;filling-the-void-bruce-k-alexander-on-the-nature-of-addictionhttpsthesunmagazineorgissues519filling-the-void&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://thesunmagazine.org/issues/519/filling-the-void&#34;&gt;Filling The Void — Bruce K Alexander on the nature of addiction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiso Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 09:26:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;shiso-water&#34;&gt;Shiso Water&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2 Shiso Leaves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1” wide slice of lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boiling water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like to make this water in the morning, before eating or drinking anything. Squeeze the lemon juice into a glass, add the leaves, and pour the water over. I’m not fully convinced about the idea of alkalizing the body through diet, however I feel like a sour drink early in the morning can relieve sugar cravings, and also improve digestion through stimulating the gallbladder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shiso (紫蘇) is also called beefsteak (?? no idea why) or perilla. It is kind of like a Japanese basil, but it comes from China originally. It is known as being very nutritious. It is used in the pickling of ume plums, and lends a pink-red color to anything it touches when wet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;紫: purple
蘇: to be resurrected, revived, rehabilitated&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Way Of Explaining</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:12:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The whole problem of existence&lt;br&gt;
is that we are are like a river, but not&lt;br&gt;
minds always flowing&lt;br&gt;
restless, unable to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sit&lt;br&gt;
by a river&lt;br&gt;
with me.&lt;br&gt;
See how the water&lt;br&gt;
moves.&lt;br&gt;
Touches&lt;br&gt;
one thing, goes on.&lt;br&gt;
Rest&lt;br&gt;
in a deep pool, behind a log.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s cold, this water.&lt;br&gt;
It will wake you up.&lt;br&gt;
This river is you, and me.&lt;br&gt;
The water is your mind.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #3</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is there something you want badly?&amp;rdquo; he asked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And she replied almost greedily, gasping for breath: &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;— and burst into a storm of weeping.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; he asked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; she wept in despair.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You needn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of telling me, Sola dear. Maybe I can get it for you when I grow up.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand. You&amp;rsquo;re so little. No one understands. I don&amp;rsquo;t even understand it myself—day and night.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Is it because of the way you&amp;rsquo;re made?&amp;rdquo; he asked, full of sympathy and conscious that the discussion was verging now upon the most intimate secrets of the human body, which it is otherwise customary never to mention — possibly it was wrong of him, but the words had slipped his tongue before he realized.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; she sighed after a little reflection, disconsolately.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter, Sola dear,&amp;rdquo; he whispered then, and patted her cheek, determined to console her. &amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s no need to find out. I won&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone. I shall ask Gvendur not to tell anyone.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;So you know, then?&amp;rdquo; she asked, taking the cloth away from her eyes and looking him straight in the eyes &amp;ldquo;— you know?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, Sola dear, I know nothing. I&amp;rsquo;ve never had a look; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter. And anyway nobody can help it. And when I&amp;rsquo;m a big man, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll build a house in another country and then you can come and live with me and eat potatoes —&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Potatoes? What do I want with potatoes?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Like it says in the Bible stories,&amp;rdquo; he explained.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;There aren&amp;rsquo;t any potatoes in the Bible stories.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I mean what the woman ate in the Bible stories,&amp;rdquo; he said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want anything in the Bible stories,&amp;rdquo; she said, gazing into space with tear-swollen eyes. &amp;ldquo;God is an enemy of the soul.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Then suddenly he asked: &amp;ldquo;What did you wish for in the winter, Sola, when the teacher gave us all a wish?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First she looked at him searchingly, and the squint in her eyes seemed more pronounced than ever, because of her weeping; then her lids fell and she began uprooting grass from the sward. &amp;ldquo;You mustn&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone,&amp;rdquo; she said.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;No, I shall never tell anyone. What was it, then?&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;It was love,&amp;rdquo; she said, and then once more her weeping burst its bonds, and again and again she repeated from the midst of her sobbing: &amp;ldquo;Love, love, love.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;How do you mean?&amp;rdquo; he asked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;She threw herself in a heap on the ground again, her shoulders shaking with sobs as they had done when he came up to her a few moments ago, and she wailed:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;I wish I could die. Die. Die.&amp;quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;He did not know what to say in the face of such sorrow. He sat in silence by his sister&amp;rsquo;s side in the spring verdure, which was too young; and the hidden strings in his breast begin to quiver, and to sound.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This was the first time he had ever looked into the labyrinth of the human soul. He was very far from understanding what he saw. But what was of more value, he felt and suffered with her. In years that were yet to come he relieved this memory in song, in the most beautiful song the world has known. For understanding the soul&amp;rsquo;s defencelessness, of the conflict between the two poles, is not the source of the greatest song. The source of the greatest song is sympathy. Sympathy with Asta Sollilja on earth.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;— Independent People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.3-tent.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;wallowa-oregon&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I drove south through the storm, the lights of Taos flickered in and out on the horizon. The snow coated the road, and driving was slow. The jeep had turned off, and I was alone. It was the hour of reflection. There was nothing to do but drive slowly, watching the road, careful with traction, looking for the edges so as not to get stuck in my little four door sedan. It lent a measure of tension to the reflections that passed through my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to go along and think: I understand this or that. Because the available material to work with, the few facts at hand, may create what looks like a full picture. The fact is, though, without knowing the full story of something, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know the complete truth. And stories can change, depending on moods, who is telling them, what is remembered and forgotten. So what is this reality we live in after all?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who am I, and what am I doing? I thought I had put these kinds of questions to rest a long time ago. But now, in my thirtieth year, I found that once again they came up, again and again. This nagging idea, that the story of my life wasn&amp;rsquo;t the point of it all, had never gone anywhere, I had never answered it. If anything, it had gone deeper, and now, at age thirty, when &amp;ldquo;something was supposed to have happened,&amp;rdquo; some career, some knowledge of the future, some success—absolutely nothing had. Even the goal I had set out to achieve four years before, which seemed reasonable to me at the time: to find a place to call home, hadn&amp;rsquo;t been achieved. The only thing I felt I had learned was that there was never a final answer to anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past my answer has been &amp;ldquo;my art&amp;rdquo; to the question of &amp;ldquo;who are you.&amp;rdquo; But as time has gone on, and my ideas of what it means to be successful have changed, and more questions have come up about the function and worth of art, and where it is useful, and who wants it, I began to doubt that. Maybe it was just a fanciful interpretation of life arisen from an easy time in my twenties. Of course people should produce beauty. Looking at the world closely, how could one not? What I had really come down to was this: did my life&amp;rsquo;s work matter to anyone else? For so long I had studied and absorbed the world, books, films, recipes, experiences. And in the back of my mind I had this idea of a reservoir of experience, building up to a shining fullness, and from that deep, bountiful place I could draw things, write things, photograph things, say things, cook things that would somehow contribute to the world around me. But in my thirtieth year, I found the world more broken than ever. The ways my friends communicated dominated by platforms engineered to be addictive. People&amp;rsquo;s attention spans shorter, and anxieties higher. City living incredibly stressful and expensive. Rural living lonely and isolating. The art, publishing, and photography worlds run by money, with frail offshoots of goodness. People&amp;rsquo;s egos getting in the way of real work. But I refused, all along, to give up the kernel question, the question from which it all sprang from for me: &amp;ldquo;What really matters?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who am I to answer such a thing, even just for myself? And trying to answer it for others? Laughable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a certain point in this quest, photography and Instagram failed me. And then words, in the way I wrote them, failed me. But, just over a year ago, I began writing about all of this anyway. I wanted to make it congeal, to have some solution from it, to understand it. So I wrote, in the night after working during the day, on a farm on an island in Maine. The writing saved my life, and gave me hope, as the time on that island was amongst the most difficult so far in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing came out as poems, instead of prose. It broke down into lines of simplistic sentences, more like short stories than anything. Over the last year I wrote almost 200 pages of this kind of writing, which I titled &amp;ldquo;A Body Of Water.&amp;rdquo; Pretty much no one, besides one or two people, have seen or heard from that work. In the midst of writing it, I realized that to some degree my questions had been answered, in that there was no answer to them. I would just have to go along and find out. Experience would offer me what I was looking for, and then again it may never.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s strange how the idea of quitting an attempt to understand something can, to me, seem almost as absurd as ever answering the question itself. And I guess that&amp;rsquo;s where I leave it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I slid into town the snow thickened, falling like flour under the orange streetlights on Paseo del Pueblo Sur. Cars had gone off the road, I counted six. The hill past the plaza was sloppy, and I turned into the curb to prevent sliding into an intersection. Everyone else was driving around gingerly, the whole world coated in pure, beautiful new snow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #2</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After leaving the retreat, I headed west and then south, across and then down the wide valley. There is only one highway bisecting the valley, mountains bordering the east, and sagelands expanding to the west. At the base of the mountains lie a huge series of pale dunes, heaped up sand and dust accumulated there over millennia, blown there by the wind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snow began to fall and then it was dark. Snow formed drifts the road, and stuck to the cold asphalt. I drove slowly, behind a jeep with their brights on, passing only one or two people as we crossed the state border.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The imaginary world that spread out beyond the headlights was full of my own thoughts, projections of what might be there. A massive, flat topped mesa? Or the Cañon de Rio Grande, where the land suddenly breaks off, space opens up, and a thread thread of green-blue runs at the bottom? Sagebrush, certainly, for miles and miles: the infinite void of sagelands that spread, almost unbroken, from here in New Mexico to southern Canada.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I drove I thought more about the retreat. I had decided I would not go to another in that tradition. I had gone because I’d never been to something like it. It was hard to know what a retreat was, and how I felt about it, before I went. To me, it felt as though a sacred tradition and culture was being sold, but I wrestled with these thoughts for weeks and even months afterwards. Was it just my own anti-establishment mindset? Or was I seeing through falsity and appropriation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While at the retreat, I had taken one morning off to go into the mountains. There was a stream flowing down, winding through aspens and cottonwoods. Ice in the stream, a little snow here and there. As I walked a dog appeared out of the trees. Seeing me she stopped, and looked expectantly. I said the magical words: “do you want to go?” And soon she was racing ahead, looking back every now and then to make sure I was still following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She led me higher and higher, back and forth across the icy stream, across roads, always looking back and waiting for me—all the way to the base of the mountains. She stopped for a drink of water, gingerly stepping on clear ice and breaking through, wetting her paws. It was strange, to meet a new friend like this, that needed no words or even a common species to experience something together. She was self-composed, she knew where she was, and where we were going. I could have walked as far as she wanted, up into the mountains, following the stream up to a lake. But we had been walking for an hour, and I knew I needed to head back. As I turned away from the path, which had began to slant upward and leave the trees behind, I wondered how far into the mountains, on this narrow path, that this simple, honest dog would have led me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived back at the car, I noticed that she had followed me all the way back. She stood at the edge of the trees, looking towards me, but not coming any closer. She had a collar, and a home—she didn’t really “need” me. But like anyone, I guess she had found walking with someone more enjoyable than going around alone. And I guess this is what I needed too—companionship, love, and someone to look for me and to look for, as we go along this old trail together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://grassjournal.co/img/19.3-dog.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;19.3-dog&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About a Meditation Retreat, #1</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The big mountains rose quickly from the flat piñon plain below. Massive, snow-capped mountains, and a sixty mile wide valley broke the scale of distance I was used to. And the weird piñons, with their twisted, old trunks, low tops, many branches: more like oaks than pine trees; held a strange presence. The plain itself savanna-like, with low grass and sagebrush, antelope, and slow-moving mule deer, who I would see in the mornings along the dry watercourses, under black cottonwoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had driven north from Taos, through the wide valley to attend a meditation retreat in the Tibetan Bön tradition, an old tradition mixing Tibetan cultural practices and Buddhism. The retreat cost around $300 for a few days sleeping in a house and a few days sitting in a big circular room, listening to a rinpoche (lit. precious one) talk about Dzogchen, a type of meditation that involves relaxation and a unique lack of effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, the first thing I noted was the number of new-model cars parked for the retreat. The majority were under five years old. A woman immediately walked up to me and said “are we supposed to park here? I’m gonna move my car. I think we’re supposed to park over there. I don’t think we can park here. I don’t know where.” She gestured vaguely towards a road running into the vast expanse of sagebrush. I shrugged and just kept walking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the entrance I was confronted by two people checking lists for names, other people milling about, a variety of scarves, shawls, baggy clothes, hiking boots, and Patagonia jackets piled in corners. The light came in precisely, very clearly, through floor to ceiling windows. It was like the light always is in the high mountains, acute and intense. We were at around 8,000 feet. Outside the mountains rose to over fourteen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I settled down on a meditation cushion in the middle of the circular conference room, a man with an unplaceable accent sat next to me. He grew up in Israel, and was Jewish. “Do you practice?” I asked. No, not really, he said. He comes to these things once or twice a year. He’s a massage therapist. He asked me what I did. I said I wandered around and wrote, making money however I could. He said I looked like a professor, but that I should give it a few years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we sat for the beginning, he leaned over from time to time to let me know what was going on. We did tsa-lung practice, a type of energetic breath and body work made to be done seated that “opens chakras.” Having never been to a retreat, but practicing meditation for about ten years alone, I found it strange to be in a room of around a hundred people, all saying the Sanksrit syllable “Ah” and imagining white light entering our bodies. Everyone else was ok with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the first morning progressed, I was struck by the humor and ease of the rinpoche. He said things like “just leave it as it is,” and “just relax,” and also “you have reflected enough!” He took questions, and carefully avoided going into people’s personal experience. He was skilled at answering questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the second day, I put up my hand and, while asking a question, made a joke. Several people laughed, as they had at many of the jokes he made. But he had an air of irritation, and as I continued my question, he said “what, is this funny or something?” I got the feeling that he was the one who could make jokes, make people laugh. Others were not allowed that liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the third and final day, we went outside for a puja. I had seen such things on documentaries, notably The Wheel of Time by Werner Herzog, where a massive hill of incense, juniper, pine wood, prayer flags, and other offerings are piled and set fire to. For our puja we had one of those cast braziers you might see at a suburban home, with a rusty metal grate. Inside a fire of piñon was made, and I was tasked with placing the crumbling, burning incense around the mesh. Rinpoche read a lot of Tibetan and everyone stood around silently, as the smoke billowed feebly from the fire, smelling like nothing really. We each took a handful of barley flour and threw it into the air, which I had also seen. In the video of the Tibetan people at the base of the Himalayas, this scene had the cameraman wading into throngs, people screaming and yelping, bells crashing, and smoke overwhelming the video, turning the screen opaque. Glimpses of weathered brown faces flitted across the screen, heavy woolen robes tied at the waist, prayer wheels, malas, lung-ta billowing, and smoke, smoke, smoke. But around me I saw the pale faced people, in nylon jackets, blankly talking and looking bored, throwing the barley when told to, laughing when queued, being silent when not, below snowy mountains that were not dissimilar to the Himalayas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I walked away, a tall white guy with long dreads came up to me. His name was Juniper, and he was from this area. He said: “we’re trying to start a little community here. I have some land. It’s an AirBnB. Next time you come through, let me know. You can stay at our AirBnB.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I headed to my car, and drove back to the newly built retreat house, to stay one last night. The house looked like it had been airlifted from a subdivision outside Omaha, Nebraska, except it was on an incredibly steep hillside, surrounded by piñons, below the snow-covered mountains. There were new washer-dryer front loading units, a giant island, new fridge, dimmable lighting, soft-closing cabinets, shiny hardwood floors. Everything inside was clean, white, new, unmarked, pure. And very, very expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/new-grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 08:03:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/new-grass/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The spaces that aren’t worth anything. Where grass comes up between broken cement slabs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quiet places that no one goes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Places that feel like they are yours, but you know they really belong to no one, and that’s why they are special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts that many think, but don’t know how to talk about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put-off ideas, made unimportant because they are frightening to confront.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humble things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are surrounded by grass. It comes up in many places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some cut it flat, then water it so it grows again. Some tear it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some let it grow until the city leaves a notice on their door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Others make grass into gardens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some bale and sell it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But much of grass is unnoticed. Special in that way, grass never asks for attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wish to.. make an art of noticing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noticing grass. You know what I mean&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By grass now&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
