<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grass Journal</title>
    <link>https://grassjournal.co/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grass Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:46:14 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiso Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 09:26:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</guid>
      <description>Shiso Water  1-2 Shiso Leaves 1&amp;rdquo; wide slice of lemon Boiling water  I like to make this water in the morning, before eating or drinking anything. Squeeze the lemon juice into a glass, add the leaves, and pour the water over. I&amp;rsquo;m not fully convinced about the idea of alkalizing the body through diet, however I feel like a sour drink early in the morning can relieve sugar cravings, and also improve digestion through stimulating the galbladder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 15:10:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>Subscribe for Bi-Weekly updates to Grass Journal.  &amp;nbsp; Enter your email address</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Way Of Explaining</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:12:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</guid>
      <description>The whole problem of existence
is that we are are like a river, but not
minds always flowing
restless, unable to stop.
Sit
by a river
with me.
See how the water
moves.
Touches
one thing, goes on.
Rest
in a deep pool, behind a log.
It’s cold, this water.
It will wake you up.
This river is you, and me.
The water is your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #3</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Is there something you want badly?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
And she replied almost greedily, gasping for breath: &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;— and burst into a storm of weeping.
&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; she wept in despair.
&amp;ldquo;You needn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of telling me, Sola dear. Maybe I can get it for you when I grow up.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand. You&amp;rsquo;re so little. No one understands. I don&amp;rsquo;t even understand it myself—day and night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #2</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</guid>
      <description>After leaving the retreat, I headed west and then south, across and then down the wide valley. There is only one highway bisecting the valley, mountains bordering the east, and sagelands expanding to the west. At the base of the mountains lie a huge series of pale dunes, heaped up sand and dust accumulated there over millennia, blown there by the wind.
Snow began to fall and then it was dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:53:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/grass/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;  Sitting quietly,
doing nothing—
spring comes;
the grass grows
by itself.
&amp;nbsp;
What Grass Is  &amp;nbsp;
The spaces that aren’t worth anything. Where grass comes up between broken cement slabs.
The quiet places that no one goes.
Places that feel like they are yours, but you know they really belong to no one, and that’s why they are special.
Thoughts that many think, but don’t know how to talk about them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:53:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/who/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; 
Hudson Gardner &amp;hellip; is fond of writing, walking, coding, and reading.
As of March 2019 he is finishing his first full-length
book of writing — A Body of Water.
He has a BA in Eastern Religion with a minor in Psychology.
He enjoys the sacred act of doing nothing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About a Meditation Retreat, #1</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</guid>
      <description>The big mountains rose quickly from the flat piñon plain below. Massive, snow-capped mountains, and a sixty mile wide valley broke the scale of distance I was used to. And the weird piñons, with their twisted, old trunks, low tops, many branches: more like oaks than pine trees; held a strange presence. The plain itself savanna-like, with low grass and sagebrush, antelope, and slow-moving mule deer, who I would see in the mornings along the dry watercourses, under black cottonwoods.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>