<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grass Journal</title>
    <link>https://grassjournal.co/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grass Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 11:37:17 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Currant Scones Of Life</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/scones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 03:53:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/scones/</guid>
      <description>These buckwheat-oatmeal scones are surprisingly delicious. Buckwheat lends a cake-like texture and roasty flavor. Additions: toasted nuts, sesame seeds, or whatever you want. Recipe by Anna.
DRY ⁘ 2 cups chosen flours (I used ¾ whole wheat, 1&amp;frasl;4 buckwheat)
⁘ 2 handfuls of oats
⁘ 1&amp;frasl;2 tsp salt
⁘ 1 tsp baking powder
⁘ Currants to taste (soak awhile in hot water)
⁘ 1 stick cold butter (cut into dry ingredients)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Dinner (Recipe)</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/late-dinner-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 20:45:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/late-dinner-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Crackly-Toasted Late Dinner Rice 😱 Rice  2 cups short grain white rice
 Water, to cover rice to a depth of 1&amp;rdquo; (or consult your rice cooker instructions)  Toppings  2 tbsp butter
 1 tbsp good soy sauce (san j, ohsawa)
 2 cloves garlic, smashed &amp;amp; chopped
 2 thinly sliced scallions  Method Put the rice and water in a pan, cover and bring to a boil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slaying The Instagram Beast</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/instagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/instagram/</guid>
      <description>In the last seven years, permit applications for entry into a certain wilderness region in Washington have risen dramatically. In 2011 about 2,800 applications were received. But in 2018 the entries had increased to over 21,500. A similar trend has occurred in other wilderness areas across the USA. Suddenly, the amount of people going to very particular, even remote places, has exploded.
There are probably many reasons why this has happened—there is a positive trend of people getting outdoors more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/spring/</guid>
      <description>There was a gap in a leafy hedge
and I watched as a little bird flew in.
Spring rises
like a green mist, up from the ground.
Water is liquid, and comes back from where it was
like spring does.
Always something coming back from something
the beat of a stone, two thumps—
the old heart again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filling The Void</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void/</guid>
      <description>About twelve years ago, when I was 18, I wound up in college. I remember lots of things from those times, but I often remember hearing how awkward everything was. Maybe it was a buzzword back in those years. I just remember the word being appended to almost every sentence any of my peers uttered. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t that awkward,&amp;rdquo; they would say, about having to talk to a teacher after class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiso Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 09:26:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</guid>
      <description>Shiso Water  1-2 Shiso Leaves 1” wide slice of lemon Boiling water  I like to make this water in the morning, before eating or drinking anything. Squeeze the lemon juice into a glass, add the leaves, and pour the water over. I’m not fully convinced about the idea of alkalizing the body through diet, however I feel like a sour drink early in the morning can relieve sugar cravings, and also improve digestion through stimulating the gallbladder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 15:10:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>Subscribe for Bi-Weekly updates to Grass Journal. Every two weeks or so I will send out an email with some of the following
A summary of what was posted here
Links to articles I&amp;rsquo;ve found interesting
Spotify playlists/albums I&amp;rsquo;ve made or enjoyed
Recipes I&amp;rsquo;ve cooked, and more.
 &amp;nbsp; Enter your email address</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Way Of Explaining</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:12:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</guid>
      <description>The whole problem of existence
is that we are are like a river, but not
minds always flowing
restless, unable to stop.
Sit
by a river
with me.
See how the water
moves.
Touches
one thing, goes on.
Rest
in a deep pool, behind a log.
It’s cold, this water.
It will wake you up.
This river is you, and me.
The water is your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #3</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Is there something you want badly?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
And she replied almost greedily, gasping for breath: &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;— and burst into a storm of weeping.
&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; she wept in despair.
&amp;ldquo;You needn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of telling me, Sola dear. Maybe I can get it for you when I grow up.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand. You&amp;rsquo;re so little. No one understands. I don&amp;rsquo;t even understand it myself—day and night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #2</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</guid>
      <description>After leaving the retreat, I headed west and then south, across and then down the wide valley. There is only one highway bisecting the valley, mountains bordering the east, and sagelands expanding to the west. At the base of the mountains lie a huge series of pale dunes, heaped up sand and dust accumulated there over millennia, blown there by the wind.
Snow began to fall and then it was dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:53:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/grass/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;  Sitting quietly,
doing nothing—
spring comes;
the grass grows
by itself.
&amp;nbsp;
About Grass Journal  &amp;nbsp;
I have always asked questions. For as long as I could articulate thoughts in words, I would ask questions that no one really knows the answers to—questions about death, meaning in life, about the universe. As I grew older, I worked very hard to not lose sight of these questions, even when everything else was telling me to focus on what was practical, answerable, and often fear-based.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:53:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/who/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; 
Hudson Gardner 川風
&amp;hellip; is fond of writing, walking, coding, reading, cooking, and growing plants.
As of March 2019 he is finishing his first full-length
book of writing — A Body of Water.
He mostly makes money through his digital skills, such as photography and writing, and also by farming, which he has been doing for the last three years.
He has a BA in Eastern Religion with a minor in Psychology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About a Meditation Retreat, #1</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</guid>
      <description>The big mountains rose quickly from the flat piñon plain below. Massive, snow-capped mountains, and a sixty mile wide valley broke the scale of distance I was used to. And the weird piñons, with their twisted, old trunks, low tops, many branches: more like oaks than pine trees; held a strange presence. The plain itself savanna-like, with low grass and sagebrush, antelope, and slow-moving mule deer, who I would see in the mornings along the dry watercourses, under black cottonwoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/new-grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 08:03:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/new-grass/</guid>
      <description>The spaces that aren’t worth anything. Where grass comes up between broken cement slabs.
The quiet places that no one goes.
Places that feel like they are yours, but you know they really belong to no one, and that’s why they are special.
Thoughts that many think, but don’t know how to talk about them.
Put-off ideas, made unimportant because they are frightening to confront.
Humble things.
.
We are surrounded by grass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>