<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grass Journal</title>
    <link>https://grassjournal.co/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Grass Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 11:37:17 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Love</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 08:51:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/love/</guid>
      <description>Maybe the important thing to remember about love is when it is held at a distance, examined, it may seem sentimental, cliché, impractical, useless, or mysterious.
But when love is experienced, it seems to be the only true reality, the only real choice one could make, or at least the best choice—it seems to clarify everything and fill the whole world.
That&amp;rsquo;s all for today.
- Hudson</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Same Day</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-same-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 10:18:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-same-day/</guid>
      <description>The red woven towel hangs limply from the oven.
I have already used it twice to dry my hands today.
The wind
outside
moves new leaves of bushes.
The ants have begun to build tunnels.
A metal shack
by the beat up street
has a padlock I have never tried to open.
The lock hangs from a handle that is rusting off.
The apricot tree nearby
has never been pruned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sun in the Morning</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-sun-in-the-morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 08:10:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-sun-in-the-morning/</guid>
      <description>The sun rises in the morning above the northern wall of the alley. The window above my shikibuton looks out onto Oregon Grape plants that now have flowers. Bees and other insects come to the flowers for the nectar. The flowers are bright yellow, the same color as the core of the plant under the bark. The plant contains berberine, which makes it incredibly bitter. The flowers become fat, deep purple berries that are both sweet and bitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worries</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 08:19:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/worries/</guid>
      <description>Laying on my back
My back begins to warm
The soft cushion of the bed
I have no plans
Only worries
I remember an ivory bear
With a turquoise arrowhead tied to it&amp;rsquo;s back
That I used to keep in a hidden wooden box
Where I used to keep my worries</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Korma</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coconut-korma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 14:43:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coconut-korma/</guid>
      <description>I have found this deceptively simple, vegan curry recipe to be just as delicious as one made with a masala. The individual flavors (garlic, ginger, cloves, cardamom) stand out more instead of getting lost in a cacophony of spices.
INGREDIENTS • 6 cloves
• 8 cardamom pods
• 1 tbsp Kashmiri chile powder, OR Korean chile powder OR whatever you have (optional)
• 1 head garlic, peeled and ground to a paste, or finely chopped (Tip: shake cloves in a jar for 2 minutes or until skins loosen)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Is a Habit</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/busy-is-a-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 07:52:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/busy-is-a-habit/</guid>
      <description>A few excerpts from The Abundance of Less  by Andy Couturier.
 &amp;ldquo;Maybe to someone else this would be terrible. But to me, I spent fifteen years traveling, and I was so satisfied doing that, when I came to this village I could live like this—&amp;rdquo; He looks around [at the barn he converted to a home] with a deeply contented and thankful expression—&amp;ldquo;I felt like I pulled off something terrific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand Dune Camp</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/sand-dune-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:45:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/sand-dune-camp/</guid>
      <description>Wide emptiness.
Spaceless nothingness.
Dust from millions of years
piled up high.
Mountains loom
but aren&amp;rsquo;t that steep.
Legs feel tired from hours of sand.
Spots of water in the dunes crooked cottonwoods
and an owl.
Fire of juniper twigs
above a dry pond.
All opens up
then closes in.
I walked so far
to get right here.
Dry creek bed
The night wind—
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come Together</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/come-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 06:17:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/come-together/</guid>
      <description>Everyone on earth has had an argument with another person. During the argument, when emotions are high, it&amp;rsquo;s often really hard to recognize the other person as human. All kinds of bad words and names come to mind. Maybe not everyone feels this way during arguments, but I know that I have.
To ameliorate the impact of arguments, I came up with an idea of agreements, which I think I first encountered talking with my mom, when we were talking about a book called The Four Agreements by Don Miguel Ruiz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortbread Cookies</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shortbread-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 07:41:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shortbread-cookies/</guid>
      <description>In the morning I make tea. And lately I have been accompanying it with a single shortbread cookie.
For a long time I resisted making delicious cookies, because the problem of sugar. But I found if I make less delicious cookies, since they are less delicious, they don&amp;rsquo;t scratch the cookie itch very well, so I end up eating more of them—which pretty much defeats the purpose of making &amp;ldquo;more healthy&amp;rdquo; cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frost&#39;s Old Woods</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/frosts-old-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 06:19:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/frosts-old-woods/</guid>
      <description>I took a break from writing over the weekend—not because I had nothing to write, but because resting the writing bone seemed like a good idea. But now that I try to write again I feel like I lost the thread I had found. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s that nothing has changed from where I was on Friday.
Over the weekend I watched the lizards and birds outside in the sun. I made chaga tea over a twig stove from a chaga conk I found in Robert Frost&amp;rsquo;s old stomping grounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Years of Growth</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/three-years-of-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 05:38:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/three-years-of-growth/</guid>
      <description>Trackless trackless mountain cloud
what do I ask to be?
To be you, to be you.
Coming—going into nothing
what do I ask to see?
To see you, to see you.
Trackless trackless mountain path
where do I ask to go?
To find you, to find you.
Trackless trackless meadow of flowers
What do I ask of you?
To believe you.
To believe you.
 Does it ever feel, to you, like you are doing what you were made to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronajournal - Cats &amp; Car Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 07:40:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing pushups lately. But my schedule is erratic. I rarely know when I will do a pushup. Sometimes I do them in the morning before I take my dogbone loop run through the dry neighborhoods. Sometimes at night just before bed. There are lots of times when I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do them, but I do them anyway.
As I write now I can hear birds outside in the chamisa, which is also called rabbitbrush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - We Are All A Part</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</guid>
      <description>Dear Corona virus,
  Welcome to Kenya. A few things you should know. Here we don&amp;rsquo;t die of flu, don&amp;rsquo;t be suprised if you fail to succeed. Usishangae [don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised], everything fails in Kenya.
We are not very excited to host you around, no offence but locusts arrived way earlier than you and first come first served, unless utoe kitu kidogo then you can skip the queue of our attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - Dishes</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</guid>
      <description>Last night I washed the dishes left over from lunch. I washed them quickly at first, since washing dishes is such a boring task that has to be done every day. Long ago, it seems, I had determined that a chore like washing dishes held no real value, except in the clean dishes maybe—but in the act, the act of washing dishes there was nothing valuable.
To wash the dishes I turned on the water until it was warm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kinnickinnic</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/kinnickinnic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 12:07:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/kinnickinnic/</guid>
      <description>Kinnickinnic
Let me tell you
a story —
It was
spring
They
two of Them
Moved through the mountains
as the snow left behind
wet rocks, trickles of
water
and cold mud—
Moved through the mountains, from low
to high, two of them
through the cold mud
and over drying rocks.
They had with them
red willow stems
from lower down
and larch boughs that they cut to sleep on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Body of Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-body-of-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 07:15:25 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-body-of-water/</guid>
      <description>About ten years ago I carried a camera with me wherever I went. It was mostly film rangefinders back then—Leicas, Bronicas, Olympus XAs, a Zeiss or two—and I had the film developed. And I scanned it myself. I posted the photos to Flickr. I had thousands of photos there. I switched to DSLRS after a while, then back and forth, then went digital for good when film developing started to get ever more expensive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gardner Farm</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/gardner-farm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2019 15:35:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/gardner-farm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/holidays/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 10:56:48 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/holidays/</guid>
      <description>Photos by Anna Every year I make a playlist of holiday music. It has a winter theme, I guess mostly drawn from the feeling of the season. Here are this year and the last two years worth—
🎄Holidays, Vol. 1
❄️Holidays, Vol. 2
⛄️Holidays, Vol. 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetry</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 06:25:42 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/poetry/</guid>
      <description>“It is difficult to get the news from poems
yet men die miserably every day
for lack of what is found there.”
 — William Carlos Williams
I remember wandering in the woods in Maine, not long ago, and I saw a tree stump. And I thought, how worthless this stump. The tree has died, and there is nothing left but a jagged place, taking up space. And yet, as we know now, trees, for some reason, keep other trees alive long after death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting A Podcast</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/starting-a-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 20:13:09 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/starting-a-podcast/</guid>
      <description>I have thought about starting a podcast for years. But the ideas never congealed. Just recently, though, I came to an idea that has some momentum. Over the last year I wrote a book called A Body of Water. The podcast will be about publishing this book.
The book itself is a loosely connected narrative of poems about my search for home over about four years time. It also has themes of impermanence, interbeing, and ecology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Share</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/why-i-share/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2019 19:40:35 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/why-i-share/</guid>
      <description>After deleting my Instagram account, I have been thinking a lot about sharing.
When I was growing up, sharing was partly learned. It felt hard at first. It usually meant giving away something that you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get back. It meant a comittment of a resource to some person or purpose. Like a juicebox at lunch, or a seat at a table.
However, once a person learns to share, it feels good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Body of Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/bodyofwater/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 19:58:40 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/bodyofwater/</guid>
      <description>A modern ecological epic  A Body of Water is a book I wrote over four years. It includes photos taken over the last decade. The writing and photos follow a narrative arc through several watersheds and ten years of time as I search for home and meaning in life. It is a story about staying true to myself. You can read a longer explanation of the project here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Ponderosa</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/three-ponderosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 22:38:10 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/three-ponderosa/</guid>
      <description>Close the eyes, and slip in
to that dark space.
A moment, then none.
No time.
I cannot explain.
Deep
in the pine woods
the water running by logs
and rafts
of flowers.
I come back, then go again.
A breath, or maybe more time passes.
In the dark: wavy changy patterns, like the bark
of Ponderosa.
The old trees dance so slow.
And the moons soft glow.
I can&amp;rsquo;t even see, anymore:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Way</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 22:33:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-way/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hard Times</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/hard-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 07:35:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/hard-times/</guid>
      <description>Things have been rough lately, or longly, for about two years now. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I wrote much about it, keeping difficulty to myself here and there, not wanting to bring anyone down, but now that I can see some kind of end, or at least some kind of change, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a few things down.
For those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, over the last four or so years Anna and I have been mostly living in remote places, far away from friends, community, and support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Progress</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/no-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 06:55:05 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/no-progress/</guid>
      <description>For many, this is where the story of their life begins.
In such a room, when they had few things, life was charted to become larger, to include more. Maybe, though, there was a part of Steve Jobs that wished he had never left that room.
For me, this is where life begins, but also where it ends. I have thought carefully about what I want, and tried things. There is something so beautiful in this empty room to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa Fe</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/santa-fe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 08:37:20 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/santa-fe/</guid>
      <description>On the corner of Cerillos and Don Diego I saw a man working on his car as I crossed the street. He had the hood up and was talking with a friend. &amp;ldquo;Is that a carbeurator?&amp;rdquo; I asked as I walked up. &amp;ldquo;Oh yeah, it&amp;rsquo;s a carbeurator. Got the original clutch in it too man, like a hundred fifty thousand on it.&amp;rdquo; We talked about how much easier it was to work on carbuerated cars rather than fuel injection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seasoned Wood</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/seasoned-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2019 14:57:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/seasoned-wood/</guid>
      <description>Seasoned Wood
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A River Flows To The Sea</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-river-flows-to-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 08:52:39 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-river-flows-to-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s something funny—
So many times I&amp;rsquo;ve been told I can&amp;rsquo;t do what I want to do, by so many people, in so many ways. It happens almost every day. And then you might think to yourself, &amp;ldquo;well, I guess this guy is just really selfish, self-centered, and ignorant.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s not true either though, because I do listen: to how plants grow, to how animals live, to how people care and support one another.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bodies - A Poem</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/bodies-a-poem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 10:56:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/bodies-a-poem/</guid>
      <description>Photo: Anna off trail in the Jemez
My body, yours
the forest floor
body of earth.
High mountains
body of stone
left alone.
Rock cañon
and a sheep skull, full curl
that nobody claimed.
Calcium, schist to granite from magma
old cottonwood, sand
thirteen tracks of a roadrunner
disappearing into the body of a desert.
Sagebrush. Chimayo. Chamisa. Conejos
river running
under a bridge.
Bosqué, cottonwoods, los alamos
huge valley, snow body</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Handbook For Ethical Instagram Use</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/a-handbook-for-ethical-instagram-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 09:18:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/a-handbook-for-ethical-instagram-use/</guid>
      <description>I started writing this out as a short post for Instagram.
I decided to put it there &amp;amp; here, because I wanted to write a little more about each point.
 Ideas For Ethical Instagram Use 1. Consider why you are posting before you post 2. Do not attempt to make your life look enviable, or better than it is For some reason, this is almost the reason Instagram exists. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a harmful practice, and creates competition and instead of collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/slow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 18:12:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/slow/</guid>
      <description>A long time ago I wrote every day for a year. That blog was called Slow Gospel.
Slow Gospel offered a space where people could slow down, even for a moment.
The entries were brief, not longer than 500 words.
That was back in 2012. Things were already humming along pretty quickly back then in the big old world.
After a year I took the site down. It did not gain an audience as I hoped it would.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hardest Work</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-hardest-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 19:12:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-hardest-work/</guid>
      <description>Photo above by Demetria Provatas, me above the Hudson River in New York
I&amp;rsquo;ll admit that I feel my work over the last year, and maybe longer, has been dark. It&amp;rsquo;s been some dark times lately, for many people. And my own individual suffering was increased by a series of mistakes I made that resulted in an abusive situation I had a difficult time extracting myself from.
I&amp;rsquo;m not asking anyone to listen to the difficulties, as I have had several willing and loving friends and family members to listen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass Roundup No. 1</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/grass-roundup-no.-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 14:20:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/grass-roundup-no.-1/</guid>
      <description>Happy April everyone, it&amp;rsquo;s the season of impatience and unpredictable weather. This is the first Grass Roundup of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve written or consumed this month. Read on for the fresh grass scent of new days and things.
Watching Firstly, a new channel by the Criterion Collection. If you&amp;rsquo;re not already an obscure film junky, you could easily become one. Before now, Criterion Collection films were only available on clunky, archaic DVD discs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lemon Currant Scones Of Life</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/scones/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 03:53:50 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/scones/</guid>
      <description>These buckwheat-oatmeal scones are surprisingly delicious. Buckwheat lends a cake-like texture and roasty flavor. Additions: toasted nuts, sesame seeds, or whatever you want. Recipe by Anna.
DRY ⁘ 2 cups chosen flours (I used ¾ whole wheat, 1/4 buckwheat)
⁘ 2 handfuls of oats
⁘ 1/2 tsp salt
⁘ 1 tsp baking powder ⁘ Currants to taste (soak awhile in hot water)
⁘ 1 stick cold butter (cut into dry ingredients)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late Dinner (Recipe)</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/late-dinner-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 20:45:19 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/late-dinner-recipe/</guid>
      <description>Crackly-Toasted Late Dinner Rice 😱 Rice  2 cups short grain white rice Water, to cover rice to a depth of 1&amp;rdquo; (or consult your rice cooker instructions)  Toppings  2 tbsp butter 1 tbsp good soy sauce (san j, ohsawa) 2 cloves garlic, smashed &amp;amp; chopped 2 thinly sliced scallions  Method Put the rice and water in a pan, cover and bring to a boil. Once it has boiled, lower the heat and simmer for 15 min (or follow rice cooker instructions).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slaying The Instagram Beast</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/instagram/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/instagram/</guid>
      <description>In the last seven years, permit applications for entry into a certain wilderness region in Washington have risen dramatically. In 2011 about 2,800 applications were received. But in 2018 the entries had increased to over 21,500. A similar trend has occurred in other wilderness areas across the USA. Suddenly, the amount of people going to very particular, even remote places, has exploded.
There are probably many reasons why this has happened—there is a positive trend of people getting outdoors more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/spring/</guid>
      <description>There was a gap in a leafy hedge
and I watched as a little bird flew in. Spring rises
like a green mist, up from the ground.
Water is liquid, and comes back from where it was
like spring does.
Always something coming back from something
the beat of a stone, two thumps—
the old heart again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Filling The Void</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/filling-the-void/</guid>
      <description>About twelve years ago, when I was 18, I wound up in college. I remember lots of things from those times, but I often remember hearing how awkward everything was. Maybe it was a buzzword back in those years. I just remember the word being appended to almost every sentence any of my peers uttered. &amp;ldquo;Isn&amp;rsquo;t that awkward,&amp;rdquo; they would say, about having to talk to a teacher after class. &amp;ldquo;He&amp;rsquo;s so awkward,&amp;rdquo; about a student whose voice cracked when asking a question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shiso Water</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 09:26:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shiso-water/</guid>
      <description>Shiso Water  1-2 Shiso Leaves 1” wide slice of lemon Boiling water  I like to make this water in the morning, before eating or drinking anything. Squeeze the lemon juice into a glass, add the leaves, and pour the water over. I’m not fully convinced about the idea of alkalizing the body through diet, however I feel like a sour drink early in the morning can relieve sugar cravings, and also improve digestion through stimulating the gallbladder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2019 15:10:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>Subscribe to Grass Newsletter A Weekly Newsletter - long walks and hikes, photos, musings on reality,
poems, tea, &amp;amp; more
 Email </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Way Of Explaining</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 13:12:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/my-way-of-explaining/</guid>
      <description>The whole problem of existence
is that we are are like a river, but not
minds always flowing
restless, unable to stop.
Sit
by a river
with me.
See how the water
moves.
Touches
one thing, goes on.
Rest
in a deep pool, behind a log.
It’s cold, this water.
It will wake you up.
This river is you, and me.
The water is your mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #3</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-03/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Is there something you want badly?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
And she replied almost greedily, gasping for breath: &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;— and burst into a storm of weeping.
&amp;ldquo;What?&amp;rdquo; he asked.
&amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know,&amp;rdquo; she wept in despair.
&amp;ldquo;You needn&amp;rsquo;t be afraid of telling me, Sola dear. Maybe I can get it for you when I grow up.&amp;quot;
&amp;ldquo;You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand. You&amp;rsquo;re so little. No one understands. I don&amp;rsquo;t even understand it myself—day and night.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About A Meditation Retreat, #2</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-02/</guid>
      <description>After leaving the retreat, I headed west and then south, across and then down the wide valley. There is only one highway bisecting the valley, mountains bordering the east, and sagelands expanding to the west. At the base of the mountains lie a huge series of pale dunes, heaped up sand and dust accumulated there over millennia, blown there by the wind.
Snow began to fall and then it was dark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:53:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/grass/</guid>
      <description>WE ARE ALL A PART Grass journal is a space of refreshing slowness.
A cool oasis of the internet.
A record of the beauty and mystery of landscapes.
I want you to spend some time here,
but you don&amp;rsquo;t have to.
The greatest asset is true freedom—
from fear, from hate, from having to do things
that don&amp;rsquo;t make any sense to you.
°
Sitting quietly,
doing nothing—
spring comes;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/who/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 22:53:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/who/</guid>
      <description>Hudson Gardner 川風
Who takes cold mountain road
takes a road that never ends.
—Han Shan (Cold Mountain), c. 800
It is necessary for the perfection of human society that there should be people who devote their lives to contemplation.
— St Thomas Aquinas, c. 1250
 At heart, I am a contemplative observer. This has led me, in turn, to living an artists life. To me specifially, that means living closely in relationship to plants, animals, and landscapes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Story About a Meditation Retreat, #1</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 08:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/meditation-01/</guid>
      <description>The big mountains rose quickly from the flat piñon plain below. Massive, snow-capped mountains, and a sixty mile wide valley broke the scale of distance I was used to. And the weird piñons, with their twisted, old trunks, low tops, many branches: more like oaks than pine trees; held a strange presence. The plain itself savanna-like, with low grass and sagebrush, antelope, and slow-moving mule deer, who I would see in the mornings along the dry watercourses, under black cottonwoods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grass</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/new-grass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2019 08:03:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/new-grass/</guid>
      <description>The spaces that aren’t worth anything. Where grass comes up between broken cement slabs.
The quiet places that no one goes.
Places that feel like they are yours, but you know they really belong to no one, and that’s why they are special.
Thoughts that many think, but don’t know how to talk about them.
Put-off ideas, made unimportant because they are frightening to confront.
Humble things.
.
We are surrounded by grass.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>