<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corona Journal on Grass Journal</title>
    <link>https://grassjournal.co/tags/corona-journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Corona Journal on Grass Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 07:40:24 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/tags/corona-journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronajournal - Cats &amp; Car Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 07:40:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing pushups lately. But my schedule is erratic. I rarely know when I will do a pushup. Sometimes I do them in the morning before I take my dogbone loop run through the dry neighborhoods. Sometimes at night just before bed. There are lots of times when I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do them, but I do them anyway.
As I write now I can hear birds outside in the chamisa, which is also called rabbitbrush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - We Are All A Part</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</guid>
      <description>Dear Corona virus,
  Welcome to Kenya. A few things you should know. Here we don&amp;rsquo;t die of flu, don&amp;rsquo;t be suprised if you fail to succeed. Usishangae [don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised], everything fails in Kenya.
We are not very excited to host you around, no offence but locusts arrived way earlier than you and first come first served, unless utoe kitu kidogo then you can skip the queue of our attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - Dishes</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</guid>
      <description>Last night I washed the dishes left over from lunch. I washed them quickly at first, since washing dishes is such a boring task that has to be done every day. Long ago, it seems, I had determined that a chore like washing dishes held no real value, except in the clean dishes maybe—but in the act, the act of washing dishes there was nothing valuable.
To wash the dishes I turned on the water until it was warm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>