<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Corona Journal on Grass Journal</title>
    <link>https://grassjournal.co/tags/corona-journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Corona Journal on Grass Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 07:11:10 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://grassjournal.co/tags/corona-journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Light Hiking New Mexico</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/light-hiking-new-mexico/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 07:11:10 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/light-hiking-new-mexico/</guid>
      <description>Up in the high valleys of the Sangre de Cristo mountains, the snow has begun to melt. Patches of snow remain below the aspen groves, or on northern slopes. High up, around 9,500 feet, the snow is still deep. Near Agua Piedra (rock water) I found a closed trail headed up to a valley. We parked the truck down the road, and walked past closed summer cabins to the beginning. A creek ran quickly to the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Same Day</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/the-same-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 10:18:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/the-same-day/</guid>
      <description>The red woven towel hangs limply from the oven.
I have already used it twice to dry my hands today.
The wind
outside
moves new leaves of bushes.
The ants have begun to build tunnels.
A metal shack
by the beat up street
has a padlock I have never tried to open.
The lock hangs from a handle that is rusting off.
The apricot tree nearby
has never been pruned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Korma</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coconut-korma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 14:43:52 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coconut-korma/</guid>
      <description>I have found this deceptively simple, vegan curry recipe to be just as delicious as one made with a masala. The individual flavors (garlic, ginger, cloves, cardamom) stand out more instead of getting lost in a cacophony of spices.
INGREDIENTS • 6 cloves
• 8 cardamom pods
• 1 tbsp Kashmiri chile powder, OR Korean chile powder OR whatever you have (optional)
• 1 head garlic, peeled and ground to a paste, or finely chopped (Tip: shake cloves in a jar for 2 minutes or until skins loosen)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Busy Is a Habit</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/busy-is-a-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 07:52:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/busy-is-a-habit/</guid>
      <description>A few excerpts from The Abundance of Less  by Andy Couturier.
 &amp;ldquo;Maybe to someone else this would be terrible. But to me, I spent fifteen years traveling, and I was so satisfied doing that, when I came to this village I could live like this—&amp;rdquo; He looks around [at the barn he converted to a home] with a deeply contented and thankful expression—&amp;ldquo;I felt like I pulled off something terrific.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sand Dune Camp</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/sand-dune-camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 06:45:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/sand-dune-camp/</guid>
      <description>Wide emptiness.
Spaceless nothingness.
Dust from millions of years
piled up high.
Mountains loom
but aren&amp;rsquo;t that steep.
Legs feel tired from hours of sand.
Spots of water in the dunes crooked cottonwoods
and an owl.
Fire of juniper twigs
above a dry pond.
All opens up
then closes in.
I walked so far
to get right here.
Dry creek bed
The night wind—
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ldquo;come over&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Come Together</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/come-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 06:17:21 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/come-together/</guid>
      <description>Everyone on earth has had an argument with another person. During the argument, when emotions are high, it&amp;rsquo;s often really hard to recognize the other person as human. All kinds of bad words and names come to mind. Maybe not everyone feels this way during arguments, but I know that I have.
To ameliorate the impact of arguments, I came up with an idea of agreements, which I think I first encountered talking with my mom, when we were talking about a book called The Four Agreements by Don Miguel Ruiz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shortbread Cookies</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/shortbread-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 07:41:58 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/shortbread-cookies/</guid>
      <description>In the morning I make tea. And lately I have been accompanying it with a single shortbread cookie.
For a long time I resisted making delicious cookies, because the problem of sugar. But I found if I make less delicious cookies, since they are less delicious, they don&amp;rsquo;t scratch the cookie itch very well, so I end up eating more of them—which pretty much defeats the purpose of making &amp;ldquo;more healthy&amp;rdquo; cookies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frost&#39;s Old Woods</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/frosts-old-woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 06:19:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/frosts-old-woods/</guid>
      <description>I took a break from writing over the weekend—not because I had nothing to write, but because resting the writing bone seemed like a good idea. But now that I try to write again I feel like I lost the thread I had found. Or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s that nothing has changed from where I was on Friday.
Over the weekend I watched the lizards and birds outside in the sun. I made chaga tea over a twig stove from a chaga conk I found in Robert Frost&amp;rsquo;s old stomping grounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three Years of Growth</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/three-years-of-growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 05:38:45 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/three-years-of-growth/</guid>
      <description>Trackless trackless mountain cloud
what do I ask to be?
To be you, to be you.
Coming—going into nothing
what do I ask to see?
To see you, to see you.
Trackless trackless mountain path
where do I ask to go?
To find you, to find you.
Trackless trackless meadow of flowers
What do I ask of you?
To believe you.
To believe you.
 Does it ever feel, to you, like you are doing what you were made to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronajournal - Cats &amp; Car Maintenance</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 07:40:24 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/coronajournal-cats-car-maintenance/</guid>
      <description>I have been doing pushups lately. But my schedule is erratic. I rarely know when I will do a pushup. Sometimes I do them in the morning before I take my dogbone loop run through the dry neighborhoods. Sometimes at night just before bed. There are lots of times when I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do them, but I do them anyway.
As I write now I can hear birds outside in the chamisa, which is also called rabbitbrush.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - We Are All A Part</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/corona-journal-we-are-all-a-part/</guid>
      <description>Dear Corona virus,
  Welcome to Kenya. A few things you should know. Here we don&amp;rsquo;t die of flu, don&amp;rsquo;t be suprised if you fail to succeed. Usishangae [don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised], everything fails in Kenya.
We are not very excited to host you around, no offence but locusts arrived way earlier than you and first come first served, unless utoe kitu kidogo then you can skip the queue of our attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corona Journal - Dishes</title>
      <link>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 07:26:44 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://grassjournal.co/dishes/</guid>
      <description>Last night I washed the dishes left over from lunch. I washed them quickly at first, since washing dishes is such a boring task that has to be done every day. Long ago, it seems, I had determined that a chore like washing dishes held no real value, except in the clean dishes maybe—but in the act, the act of washing dishes there was nothing valuable.
To wash the dishes I turned on the water until it was warm.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>